<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Medicinal Plants Information</string>

    <style name="NoActionBar" parent="Theme.AppCompat.DayNight.NoActionBar">
        <item name="colorPrimary">@color/design_default_color_primary</item>
        <item name="colorPrimaryDark">@color/design_default_color_primary_dark</item>
        <item name="colorAccent">@color/design_default_color_background</item>
    </style>

    <style name="round" parent="">
        <item name="cornerFamily">rounded</item>
        <item name="cornerSize">@dimen/_20sdp</item>

    </style>

    <!--    //variable name-->
    <string name="Local_name">Local Name:-</string>
    <string name="scientific_name">Scientific Name:-</string>
    <string name="family">Fanily:-</string>
    <string name="Description">Description:-</string>
    <string name="Distribution">Distribution:-</string>
    <string name="Medicinal_uses">Medicinal Uses:-</string>
    <string name="Benifits">Benifits:-</string>
    <string name="Side_Effects">Side Effects:-</string>


    <!--    //plants name -->
    <string name="p1">Acacia nilotica</string>
    <string name="p2">Acalypha indica</string>
    <string name="p3">Allium sativum</string>
    <string name="p4">Anethum graveolens</string>
    <string name="p5">Argyreia nervosa</string>
    <string name="p6">Asparagus racemosus</string>
    <!--    <string name="p7"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p8"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p9"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p10"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p11"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p12"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p13"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p14"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p15"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p16"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="p17"></string>-->


    <!--    local name -->
    <string name="l1">Baval</string>
    <string name="l2">Dadro</string>
    <string name="l3">Lasan</string>
    <string name="l4">Suva</string>
    <string name="l5">Vardharo</string>
    <string name="l6">Vechhekato</string>


    <!--        Scientific Name:- -->
    <string name="s1">Vachellia nilotica</string>
    <string name="s2">Acalypha indica</string>
    <string name="s3">Allium sativum</string>
    <string name="s4"> Anethum graveolens</string>
    <string name="s5"> Argyreia nervosa</string>
    <string name="s6">Asparagus racemosus</string>


    <!--        Family-->
    <string name="f1">Fabaceae</string>
    <string name="f2">Euphorbiaceae</string>
    <string name="f3">Amaryllidaceae</string>
    <string name="f4">Apiaceae</string>
    <string name="f5">Convolvulaceae</string>
    <string name="f6">Asparagaceae</string>


    <!--    description-->
    <string name="d1">Acacia nilotica or Vachellia nilotica is a tree 5–20 m high with a dense spheric crown, stems and branches usually dark to black coloured, fissured bark, grey-pinkish slash, exuding a reddish low quality gum.The tree has thin, straight, light, grey spines in axillary pairs, usually in 3 to 12 pairs, 5 to 7.5 cm (3 in) long in young trees, mature trees commonly without thorns. The leaves are bipinnate, with 3–6 pairs of pinnulae and 10–30 pairs of leaflets each, tomentose, rachis with a gland at the bottom of the last pair of pinnulae. Flowers in globulous heads 1.2–1.5 cm in diameter of a bright golden-yellow color, set up either axillary or whorly on peduncles 2–3 cm long located at the end of the branches. Pods are strongly constricted, hairy, white-grey, thick and softly tomentose. Its seeds number approximately 8000/kg</string>
    <string name="d2">An erect annual herb that can be easily distinguished by the cup-shaped involucre that surrounds the small flowers in the catkin-like inflorescence.It can grow up to 1.2 m (3.9 ft) tall in favorable circumstances, but is usually smaller. The leaves are broad ovate, 1.2 cm–6.5 cm × 1 cm–4 cm (0.47 in–2.56 in × 0.39 in–1.57 in). The leaf base is rounded to shortly attenuate. The leaf margin is basally 5-nerved and is crenate-serrate with an acute or obtuse apex. The petiole is 1.5–5.5 cm (0.59–2.17 in) long.</string>
    <string name="d3">Allium sativum is a perennial flowering plant that grows from a bulb. It has a tall, erect flowering stem that grows up to 1 m (3 ft). The leaf blade is flat, linear, solid, and approximately 1.25–2.5 cm (0.5–1.0 in) wide, with an acute apex. The plant may produce pink to purple flowers from July to September in the Northern Hemisphere. The bulb has a strong odor and is typically made up of 10 to 20 cloves. The cloves close to the center are symmetrical, and those surrounding the center can be asymmetrical. Each clove is enclosed in an inner sheathing leaf surrounded by layers of outer sheathing leaves. If garlic is planted at the proper time and depth, it can be grown as far north as Alaska. It produces hermaphroditic flowers. It is pollinated by bees, butterflies, moths, and other insects.</string>
    <string name="d4">Anethum graveolens, or dill, is an aromatic and flavorful herb widely used in culinary dishes and traditional medicine. It is an annual herb that typically grows to a height of 40 to 60 centimeters (16 to 24 inches). Dill plants have feathery, finely divided leaves that resemble delicate fern fronds. The plant produces small, yellow flowers that form umbrella-like clusters, and eventually, it develops small, oval-shaped seeds known as dill seeds, which are used as a spice.</string>
    <string name="d5">Hawaiian baby woodrose is a perennial climbing vine that can reach lengths of up to 100 feet (30 meters).Its leaves are heart-shaped, and the plant produces large, trumpet-shaped flowers with a white to lavender color.The seeds of this plant are particularly notable; they are brown to black and contain psychoactive compounds.</string>
    <string name="d6">Asparagus racemosus is a herbaceous, perennial plant native to India and some parts of Southeast Asia. It is a climber with feathery, needle-like leaves and produces small, fragrant, and white flowers. The plant has a tuberous root system, which is the most commonly used part for medicinal purposes. The roots are long, succulent, and have a creamy-white color.</string>

    <!--    distribution-->
    <string name="dt1">Acacia nilotica or Vachellia nilotica is native from Egypt, across the Maghreb and Sahel, south to Mozambique and KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa, and east through the Arabian Peninsula to the Indian subcontinent and Burma. It has become widely naturalised outside its native range including Zanzibar and Australia.It is spread by livestock.</string>
    <string name="dt2">Acalypha indica occurs widely throughout the Old World tropics. In Africa, it occurs in Nigeria in West Africa and further widely throughout tropical Africa and the Indian Ocean islands. It also occurs in India, South East Asia, Yemen, and Oceania. It has been introduced to the New World Tropics.</string>
    <string name="dt3">Allium is an ancient crop that has its origins in central Asia and is widely distributed throughout the temperate, warm temperate, and boreal zones of the northern hemisphere</string>
    <string name="dt4">Dill is native to the Mediterranean region and Southern Europe, but it is now cultivated and grown in various parts of the world. It is a popular herb in many cuisines, including European, Middle Eastern, and Indian cuisines.</string>
    <string name="dt5">Native to India, it can also be found in various parts of Southeast Asia, including Hawaii, where it has become naturalized.Due to its ornamental appeal and psychoactive properties, it has been introduced and cultivated in other regions as well.</string>
    <string name="dt6">Asparagus racemosus is primarily found in India, particularly in the Himalayan regions, as well as in other parts of South Asia. It thrives in tropical and subtropical regions.</string>


    <!--    medicinal uses:- -->
    <string name="m1">In traditional medicine, Acacia Nilotica is widely used. This plant has anti-microbial,anti-plasmodial and antioxidant activity and used for treatment of human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis C virus and cancer. 7 It is useful for treatment of venereal diseases, nausea, burns and wounds, stomachache and diarrhea</string>
    <string name="m2">Based on literature studies, Acalypha indica has the capability to serve as anthelmintic, anti-inflammation, anti-bacterial, anti-cancer, anti-diabetes, anti-hyperlipidemic, anti-obesity, anti-venom, hepatoprotective, hypoxia, and wound healing medicine.</string>
    <string name="m3">Garlic cloves have antilipemic (cholesterol-lowering), antihypertensive, antimicrobial, and anticancer qualities, all of which help prevent cancer cells from forming in the stomach, liver, and other human organs , and also help with asthma, arthritis, back pain, bronchitis, chronic fever, tuberculosis, rhinitis, malaria, stubborn skin conditions including leprosy, leucoderma, skin discoloration, and itching colic, enlarged spleen, hemorrhoids, fistula, bone fracture, gout, urinary tract disease, diabetes, and kidney stone</string>
    <string name="m4">Dill has been used in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda, for its potential medicinal properties. Some of the traditional medicinal uses of dill include:Digestive Aid: Dill is known for its carminative properties, which means it can help relieve digestive discomfort, reduce gas, and alleviate bloating.Anti-inflammatory: It is used to reduce inflammation and soothe conditions like indigestion and gastritis.Antispasmodic: Dill is believed to have antispasmodic effects and can help relax muscles, including those in the digestive tract, providing relief from cramps.Diuretic: It may promote urination and help in flushing out excess fluids and toxins from the body.Galactagogue: In some cultures, dill is used to promote milk production in breastfeeding mothers.</string>
    <string name="m5">Traditional medicine in some regions has employed Argyreia nervosa for various purposes.In Ayurvedic medicine, it has been used for its potential as a nervine tonic, as well as for its purported aphrodisiac properties.The seeds are sometimes used to treat conditions like asthma, coughs, and bronchitis in traditional systems of medicine.</string>
    <string name="m6">Shatavari has a long history of use in traditional Ayurvedic medicine and is highly regarded for its medicinal properties. It is primarily known for its role in supporting female reproductive health but offers several other health benefits as well.Female Reproductive Health: Shatavari is often used to regulate menstrual cycles, alleviate symptoms of menopause, and promote lactation in breastfeeding mothers.Digestive Health: It can help soothe digestive discomfort, reduce acidity, and promote healthy digestion.Immune System: Shatavari has immunomodulatory properties, which means it can enhance the body\'s immune response.Anti-inflammatory: It exhibits anti-inflammatory properties and may help in conditions characterized by inflammation.Antioxidant: Shatavari is rich in antioxidants, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage.Adaptogen: It is considered an adaptogen, helping the body adapt to stress and maintain balance.</string>

    <!--    Benifit:- -->
    <string name="b1">nilotica fruit is used for the treatment of sore throat, cold, bronchitis, pneumonia, ophthalmia, diarrhoea, dysentery, leprosy and venereal diseases as per Unani traditional medicine.</string>
    <string name="b2">Based on literature studies, Acalypha indica has the capability to serve as anthelmintic, anti-inflammation, anti-bacterial, anti-cancer, anti-diabetes, anti-hyperlipidemic, anti-obesity, anti-venom, hepatoprotective, hypoxia, and wound healing medicine.</string>
    <string name="b3">Garlic inhibits and destroys bacteria, fungus, and parasites, as well as lowers blood pressure, cholesterol, and sugar levels, preventing blood clotting and protecting the liver. It also has anticancer effects . Garlic can also help to improve the immune system, prevent sickness, and preserve good health</string>
    <string name="b4">Dill offers several potential health benefits, primarily related to its traditional medicinal uses:Digestive Health: Dill can support healthy digestion, alleviate gas and bloating, and reduce indigestion.Anti-inflammatory: It may help reduce inflammation, especially in the digestive tract.Antispasmodic: Dill\'s antispasmodic properties can provide relief from muscle cramps and spasms.Diuretic Effects: It may help maintain fluid balance and promote the removal of waste products from the body.Breastfeeding Support: Dill is used in some cultures to increase milk production in nursing mothers.</string>
    <string name="b5">psychoactive compounds found in Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds, particularly ergine (also known as LSA or lysergic acid amide), can induce hallucinogenic and psychedelic effects when ingested.Some individuals have reported experiencing altered states of consciousness, vivid visual and auditory hallucinations, and a sense of interconnectedness with the universe after consuming these seeds.In some cultures, it has been used in shamanic or spiritual rituals for its mind-altering effects.</string>
    <string name="b6">The benefits of Shatavari include improved reproductive health, relief from digestive issues, enhanced immune function, reduced inflammation, and overall well-being. It is particularly beneficial for women\'s health, including regulating menstrual cycles, managing PMS symptoms, and supporting lactation.</string>

    <!--    Side Effects:- -->
    <string name="se1">Acacia is LIKELY SAFE for most adults when taken by mouth in amounts commonly found in food. Acacia is POSSIBLY SAFE when taken by mouth in amounts used for medical purposes. Up to 30 grams daily has been used safely for 6 weeks. However, it can cause minor adverse effects, including gas, bloating, nausea, and loose stools.</string>
    <string name="se2">Some of the chemical compounds in Acalypha indica cause dark chocolate-brown discoloration of blood, and gastrointestinal irritation in rabbits. Ingestion of Acalypha indica may lead to hemolysis in people suffering from glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency.</string>
    <string name="se3">Breath and body odor, upset stomach, or heartburn may occur. If any of these effects persist or worsen, contact your doctor or pharmacist promptly. Tell your doctor immediately if any of these rare but very serious side effects occur: easy or unusual bruising/bleeding</string>
    <string name="se4">Dill is generally safe for most people when consumed in culinary amounts. However, there are a few considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to dill and could experience allergic reactions, such as skin rashes or itching.Pregnancy: While dill is generally considered safe in culinary amounts during pregnancy, high doses or medicinal use of dill should be avoided during pregnancy unless under the guidance of a healthcare provider.Blood Clotting: Dill may have mild blood-thinning effects, so individuals on blood-thinning medications should exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider.Herb-Drug Interactions: Dill supplements or extracts may interact with certain medications. If you are on medication, consult with a healthcare provider before using dill supplements for therapeutic purposes.</string>
    <string name="se5">The consumption of Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds can be associated with a range of side effects, including:Nausea and vomiting,Stomach discomfort,Dizziness,Confusion,Anxiety and panic attacks,Unpleasant or challenging hallucinationsIt\'s essential to note that the psychoactive effects of these seeds can be unpredictable and vary from person to person.There is a risk of overdose, which can lead to more severe symptoms and even medical complications.Long-term or frequent use of Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds can potentially have adverse effects on mental health.</string>
    <string name="se6">Shatavari is generally considered safe when consumed at recommended doses. However, some individuals may experience mild side effects, such as gastrointestinal discomfort or allergic reactions. It is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using Shatavari, especially if you are pregnant, nursing, or have any underlying medical conditions.Please note that while Shatavari has been used for centuries in traditional medicine, it\'s essential to consult with a qualified healthcare practitioner or Ayurvedic specialist for proper guidance and dosage recommendations based on your specific health needs and conditions. Additionally, the information provided here is based on historical and traditional uses, and scientific research may continue to uncover more about its potential benefits and side effects.
</string>

</resources>