<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Medicinal Plants Information</string>

    <style name="NoActionBar" parent="Theme.AppCompat.DayNight.NoActionBar">
        <item name="colorPrimary">@color/design_default_color_primary</item>
        <item name="colorPrimaryDark">@color/design_default_color_primary_dark</item>
        <item name="colorAccent">@color/design_default_color_background</item>
    </style>

    <style name="round" parent="">
        <item name="cornerFamily">rounded</item>
        <item name="cornerSize">@dimen/_20sdp</item>

    </style>

    <!--    //variable name-->
    <string name="Local_name">Local Name:-</string>
    <string name="scientific_name">Scientific Name:-</string>
    <string name="family">Family:-</string>
    <string name="Description">Description:-</string>
    <string name="Distribution">Distribution:-</string>
    <string name="Medicinal_uses">Medicinal Uses:-</string>
    <string name="Benifits">Benifits:-</string>
    <string name="Side_Effects">Side Effects:-</string>


    <!--    //plants name -->
    <string name="p1">Acacia nilotica</string>
    <string name="p2">Acalypha indica</string>
    <string name="p3">Allium sativum</string>
    <string name="p4">Anethum graveolens</string>
    <string name="p5">Argyreia nervosa</string>
    <string name="p6">Asparagus racemosus</string>
    <string name="p7">Barleria Prionitis</string>


    <!--    local name -->
    <string name="l1">Baval</string>
    <string name="l2">Dadro</string>
    <string name="l3">Lasan</string>
    <string name="l4">Suva</string>
    <string name="l5">Vardharo</string>
    <string name="l6">Vechhekato</string>
    <string name="l7">Kantashario</string>


    <!--        Scientific Name:- -->
    <string name="s1">Vachellia nilotica</string>
    <string name="s2">Acalypha indica</string>
    <string name="s3">Allium sativum</string>
    <string name="s4"> Anethum graveolens</string>
    <string name="s5"> Argyreia nervosa</string>
    <string name="s6">Asparagus racemosus</string>
    <string name="s7">Barleria prionitis</string>


    <!--        Family-->
    <string name="f1">Fabaceae</string>
    <string name="f2">Euphorbiaceae</string>
    <string name="f3">Amaryllidaceae</string>
    <string name="f4">Apiaceae</string>
    <string name="f5">Convolvulaceae</string>
    <string name="f6">Asparagaceae</string>
    <string name="f7">Acanthaceae</string>


    <!--    description-->
    <string name="d1">Acacia nilotica or Vachellia nilotica is a tree 5–20 m high with a dense spheric crown, stems and branches usually dark to black coloured, fissured bark, grey-pinkish slash, exuding a reddish low quality gum.The tree has thin, straight, light, grey spines in axillary pairs, usually in 3 to 12 pairs, 5 to 7.5 cm (3 in) long in young trees, mature trees commonly without thorns. The leaves are bipinnate, with 3–6 pairs of pinnulae and 10–30 pairs of leaflets each, tomentose, rachis with a gland at the bottom of the last pair of pinnulae. Flowers in globulous heads 1.2–1.5 cm in diameter of a bright golden-yellow color, set up either axillary or whorly on peduncles 2–3 cm long located at the end of the branches. Pods are strongly constricted, hairy, white-grey, thick and softly tomentose. Its seeds number approximately 8000/kg</string>
    <string name="d2">An erect annual herb that can be easily distinguished by the cup-shaped involucre that surrounds the small flowers in the catkin-like inflorescence.It can grow up to 1.2 m (3.9 ft) tall in favorable circumstances, but is usually smaller. The leaves are broad ovate, 1.2 cm–6.5 cm × 1 cm–4 cm (0.47 in–2.56 in × 0.39 in–1.57 in). The leaf base is rounded to shortly attenuate. The leaf margin is basally 5-nerved and is crenate-serrate with an acute or obtuse apex. The petiole is 1.5–5.5 cm (0.59–2.17 in) long.</string>
    <string name="d3">Allium sativum is a perennial flowering plant that grows from a bulb. It has a tall, erect flowering stem that grows up to 1 m (3 ft). The leaf blade is flat, linear, solid, and approximately 1.25–2.5 cm (0.5–1.0 in) wide, with an acute apex. The plant may produce pink to purple flowers from July to September in the Northern Hemisphere. The bulb has a strong odor and is typically made up of 10 to 20 cloves. The cloves close to the center are symmetrical, and those surrounding the center can be asymmetrical. Each clove is enclosed in an inner sheathing leaf surrounded by layers of outer sheathing leaves. If garlic is planted at the proper time and depth, it can be grown as far north as Alaska. It produces hermaphroditic flowers. It is pollinated by bees, butterflies, moths, and other insects.</string>
    <string name="d4">Anethum graveolens, or dill, is an aromatic and flavorful herb widely used in culinary dishes and traditional medicine. It is an annual herb that typically grows to a height of 40 to 60 centimeters (16 to 24 inches). Dill plants have feathery, finely divided leaves that resemble delicate fern fronds. The plant produces small, yellow flowers that form umbrella-like clusters, and eventually, it develops small, oval-shaped seeds known as dill seeds, which are used as a spice.</string>
    <string name="d5">Hawaiian baby woodrose is a perennial climbing vine that can reach lengths of up to 100 feet (30 meters).Its leaves are heart-shaped, and the plant produces large, trumpet-shaped flowers with a white to lavender color.The seeds of this plant are particularly notable; they are brown to black and contain psychoactive compounds.</string>
    <string name="d6">Asparagus racemosus is a herbaceous, perennial plant native to India and some parts of Southeast Asia. It is a climber with feathery, needle-like leaves and produces small, fragrant, and white flowers. The plant has a tuberous root system, which is the most commonly used part for medicinal purposes. The roots are long, succulent, and have a creamy-white color.</string>
    <string name="d7">
        <br>Barleria prionitis, commonly known as Porcupine Flower, is a spiny, woody shrub or small tree that can grow up to 2-3 meters in height</br>
        <br>The plant has simple, opposite leaves that are elliptic to oblong and covered with fine hairs.</br>
        <br>It produces bright orange or yellow tubular flowers that are arranged in clusters and have a spiny, cylindrical calyx.</br>
        <br>The plant is characterized by its spiny nature, with sharp, needle-like thorns found along the stems and branches.</br>

    </string>


    <!--    distribution-->
    <string name="dt1">Acacia nilotica or Vachellia nilotica is native from Egypt, across the Maghreb and Sahel, south to Mozambique and KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa, and east through the Arabian Peninsula to the Indian subcontinent and Burma. It has become widely naturalised outside its native range including Zanzibar and Australia.It is spread by livestock.</string>
    <string name="dt2">Acalypha indica occurs widely throughout the Old World tropics. In Africa, it occurs in Nigeria in West Africa and further widely throughout tropical Africa and the Indian Ocean islands. It also occurs in India, South East Asia, Yemen, and Oceania. It has been introduced to the New World Tropics.</string>
    <string name="dt3">Allium is an ancient crop that has its origins in central Asia and is widely distributed throughout the temperate, warm temperate, and boreal zones of the northern hemisphere</string>
    <string name="dt4">Dill is native to the Mediterranean region and Southern Europe, but it is now cultivated and grown in various parts of the world. It is a popular herb in many cuisines, including European, Middle Eastern, and Indian cuisines.</string>
    <string name="dt5">Native to India, it can also be found in various parts of Southeast Asia, including Hawaii, where it has become naturalized.Due to its ornamental appeal and psychoactive properties, it has been introduced and cultivated in other regions as well.</string>
    <string name="dt6">Asparagus racemosus is primarily found in India, particularly in the Himalayan regions, as well as in other parts of South Asia. It thrives in tropical and subtropical regions.</string>
    <string name="dt7">
        <br>Barleria prionitis is native to South Asia and is found in various countries, including India, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, Pakistan, and parts of Southeast Asia.</br>
        <br>It is well-adapted to tropical and subtropical regions and can be found in a variety of habitats, including forests, grasslands, and disturbed areas.</br>

    </string>

    <!--    medicinal uses:- -->
    <string name="m1">In traditional medicine, Acacia Nilotica is widely used. This plant has anti-microbial,anti-plasmodial and antioxidant activity and used for treatment of human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis C virus and cancer. 7 It is useful for treatment of venereal diseases, nausea, burns and wounds, stomachache and diarrhea</string>
    <string name="m2">Based on literature studies, Acalypha indica has the capability to serve as anthelmintic, anti-inflammation, anti-bacterial, anti-cancer, anti-diabetes, anti-hyperlipidemic, anti-obesity, anti-venom, hepatoprotective, hypoxia, and wound healing medicine.</string>
    <string name="m3">Garlic cloves have antilipemic (cholesterol-lowering), antihypertensive, antimicrobial, and anticancer qualities, all of which help prevent cancer cells from forming in the stomach, liver, and other human organs , and also help with asthma, arthritis, back pain, bronchitis, chronic fever, tuberculosis, rhinitis, malaria, stubborn skin conditions including leprosy, leucoderma, skin discoloration, and itching colic, enlarged spleen, hemorrhoids, fistula, bone fracture, gout, urinary tract disease, diabetes, and kidney stone</string>
    <string name="m4">Dill has been used in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda, for its potential medicinal properties. Some of the traditional medicinal uses of dill include:Digestive Aid: Dill is known for its carminative properties, which means it can help relieve digestive discomfort, reduce gas, and alleviate bloating.Anti-inflammatory: It is used to reduce inflammation and soothe conditions like indigestion and gastritis.Antispasmodic: Dill is believed to have antispasmodic effects and can help relax muscles, including those in the digestive tract, providing relief from cramps.Diuretic: It may promote urination and help in flushing out excess fluids and toxins from the body.Galactagogue: In some cultures, dill is used to promote milk production in breastfeeding mothers.</string>
    <string name="m5">Traditional medicine in some regions has employed Argyreia nervosa for various purposes.In Ayurvedic medicine, it has been used for its potential as a nervine tonic, as well as for its purported aphrodisiac properties.The seeds are sometimes used to treat conditions like asthma, coughs, and bronchitis in traditional systems of medicine.</string>
    <string name="m6">Shatavari has a long history of use in traditional Ayurvedic medicine and is highly regarded for its medicinal properties. It is primarily known for its role in supporting female reproductive health but offers several other health benefits as well.Female Reproductive Health: Shatavari is often used to regulate menstrual cycles, alleviate symptoms of menopause, and promote lactation in breastfeeding mothers.Digestive Health: It can help soothe digestive discomfort, reduce acidity, and promote healthy digestion.Immune System: Shatavari has immunomodulatory properties, which means it can enhance the body\'s immune response.Anti-inflammatory: It exhibits anti-inflammatory properties and may help in conditions characterized by inflammation.Antioxidant: Shatavari is rich in antioxidants, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage.Adaptogen: It is considered an adaptogen, helping the body adapt to stress and maintain balance.</string>
    <string name="m7">

        <br>Barleria prionitis has a long history of medicinal use in traditional systems of medicine, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine.</br>
        <br>The plant has various medicinal properties and is used for the treatment of several ailments.</br>
        <br>It is considered to be a valuable herb for oral health and is used in toothpaste and oral care products due to its antibacterial properties.</br>
        <br>In Ayurveda, the root of the plant is used to prepare medicinal formulations to treat various conditions, including dental problems, fever, cough, and digestive disorders.</br>
        <br>The leaves and roots are also used as an anti-inflammatory and analgesic agent in traditional medicine.</br>


    </string>


    <!--    Benifit:- -->
    <string name="b1">nilotica fruit is used for the treatment of sore throat, cold, bronchitis, pneumonia, ophthalmia, diarrhoea, dysentery, leprosy and venereal diseases as per Unani traditional medicine.</string>
    <string name="b2">Based on literature studies, Acalypha indica has the capability to serve as anthelmintic, anti-inflammation, anti-bacterial, anti-cancer, anti-diabetes, anti-hyperlipidemic, anti-obesity, anti-venom, hepatoprotective, hypoxia, and wound healing medicine.</string>
    <string name="b3">Garlic inhibits and destroys bacteria, fungus, and parasites, as well as lowers blood pressure, cholesterol, and sugar levels, preventing blood clotting and protecting the liver. It also has anticancer effects . Garlic can also help to improve the immune system, prevent sickness, and preserve good health</string>
    <string name="b4">Dill offers several potential health benefits, primarily related to its traditional medicinal uses:Digestive Health: Dill can support healthy digestion, alleviate gas and bloating, and reduce indigestion.Anti-inflammatory: It may help reduce inflammation, especially in the digestive tract.Antispasmodic: Dill\'s antispasmodic properties can provide relief from muscle cramps and spasms.Diuretic Effects: It may help maintain fluid balance and promote the removal of waste products from the body.Breastfeeding Support: Dill is used in some cultures to increase milk production in nursing mothers.</string>
    <string name="b5">psychoactive compounds found in Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds, particularly ergine (also known as LSA or lysergic acid amide), can induce hallucinogenic and psychedelic effects when ingested.Some individuals have reported experiencing altered states of consciousness, vivid visual and auditory hallucinations, and a sense of interconnectedness with the universe after consuming these seeds.In some cultures, it has been used in shamanic or spiritual rituals for its mind-altering effects.</string>
    <string name="b6">The benefits of Shatavari include improved reproductive health, relief from digestive issues, enhanced immune function, reduced inflammation, and overall well-being. It is particularly beneficial for women\'s health, including regulating menstrual cycles, managing PMS symptoms, and supporting lactation.</string>
    <string name="b7">
        <br>Oral Health: Barleria prionitis is known for its role in maintaining oral hygiene. It is used to treat dental issues such as toothache, gum infections, and bad breath.</br>
        <br>Anti-Inflammatory: The plant has anti-inflammatory properties and can be used topically to reduce inflammation and pain in conditions like arthritis and joint pain.</br>
        <br>Fever Reduction: In traditional medicine, it is used to reduce fever and as a febrifuge.</br>
        <br>Digestive Health: Some traditional remedies use Barleria prionitis to improve digestion and treat gastrointestinal disorders.</br>




    </string>


    <!--    Side Effects:- -->
    <string name="se1">Acacia is LIKELY SAFE for most adults when taken by mouth in amounts commonly found in food. Acacia is POSSIBLY SAFE when taken by mouth in amounts used for medical purposes. Up to 30 grams daily has been used safely for 6 weeks. However, it can cause minor adverse effects, including gas, bloating, nausea, and loose stools.</string>
    <string name="se2">Some of the chemical compounds in Acalypha indica cause dark chocolate-brown discoloration of blood, and gastrointestinal irritation in rabbits. Ingestion of Acalypha indica may lead to hemolysis in people suffering from glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency.</string>
    <string name="se3">Breath and body odor, upset stomach, or heartburn may occur. If any of these effects persist or worsen, contact your doctor or pharmacist promptly. Tell your doctor immediately if any of these rare but very serious side effects occur: easy or unusual bruising/bleeding</string>
    <string name="se4">Dill is generally safe for most people when consumed in culinary amounts. However, there are a few considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to dill and could experience allergic reactions, such as skin rashes or itching.Pregnancy: While dill is generally considered safe in culinary amounts during pregnancy, high doses or medicinal use of dill should be avoided during pregnancy unless under the guidance of a healthcare provider.Blood Clotting: Dill may have mild blood-thinning effects, so individuals on blood-thinning medications should exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider.Herb-Drug Interactions: Dill supplements or extracts may interact with certain medications. If you are on medication, consult with a healthcare provider before using dill supplements for therapeutic purposes.</string>
    <string name="se5">The consumption of Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds can be associated with a range of side effects, including:Nausea and vomiting,Stomach discomfort,Dizziness,Confusion,Anxiety and panic attacks,Unpleasant or challenging hallucinationsIt\'s essential to note that the psychoactive effects of these seeds can be unpredictable and vary from person to person.There is a risk of overdose, which can lead to more severe symptoms and even medical complications.Long-term or frequent use of Hawaiian baby woodrose seeds can potentially have adverse effects on mental health.</string>
    <string name="se6">Shatavari is generally considered safe when consumed at recommended doses. However, some individuals may experience mild side effects, such as gastrointestinal discomfort or allergic reactions. It is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using Shatavari, especially if you are pregnant, nursing, or have any underlying medical conditions.Please note that while Shatavari has been used for centuries in traditional medicine, it\'s essential to consult with a qualified healthcare practitioner or Ayurvedic specialist for proper guidance and dosage recommendations based on your specific health needs and conditions. Additionally, the information provided here is based on historical and traditional uses, and scientific research may continue to uncover more about its potential benefits and side effects.</string>
    <string name="se7">

        <br>While Barleria prionitis has several medicinal benefits, its use should be done with caution, especially in high doses or without proper guidance. Potential side effects and considerations include:</br>
        <br>Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to the plant, leading to skin rashes or other allergic symptoms.Digestive Issues: Excessive consumption may lead to gastrointestinal discomfort</br>
        <br>Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and nursing women should avoid using this plant without consulting a healthcare professional</br>
        <br>Interaction with Medications: It may interact with certain medications, so consult a healthcare provider before using it alongside other drugs.</br>
        <br>Always consult a qualified healthcare practitioner or an Ayurvedic expert before using Barleria prionitis or any other herbal remedy for medicinal purposes to ensure it is safe and appropriate for your specific condition.</br>
    </string>


    <string name="p8">Cajanus cajan </string>
    <string name="s8">Cajanus cajan</string>
    <string name="l8">Tuver</string>
    <string name="f8">Fabaceae</string>
    <string name="d8">Pigeon pea is a perennial shrub that can grow up to 1-4 meters in height. It has compound leaves with three leaflets and produces bright yellow or orange flowers. The most distinctive feature of the plant is its long, slender, and cylindrical pods that contain the edible seeds. The seeds can vary in color, including red, green, yellow, and brown, depending on the variety.</string>
    <string name="dt8">Pigeon pea is native to tropical and subtropical regions of the Indian subcontinent. It is widely cultivated in countries such as India, Nigeria, Myanmar, Brazil, and many others in Asia, Africa, and the Americas. Due to its adaptability to various soil types and climate conditions, pigeon pea has become an important crop in many parts of the world.</string>
    <string name="m8">Digestive Health: Pigeon pea is known for its digestive benefits. It contains dietary fiber, which helps in regulating bowel movements and preventing constipation.Diabetes Management: Some studies suggest that pigeon pea may help regulate blood sugar levels due to its low glycemic index and potential to improve insulin sensitivity.Anti-Inflammatory Properties: The plant has anti-inflammatory compounds that may be beneficial for reducing inflammation and related conditions.Antioxidant Properties: Pigeon pea seeds contain antioxidants, such as flavonoids and polyphenols, which can help protect cells from oxidative stress.Wound Healing: In traditional medicine, pigeon pea paste is used topically on wounds to promote healing.Respiratory Health: In some regions, pigeon pea is used to treat respiratory ailments, such as coughs and bronchitis.</string>
    <string name="b8">Pigeon pea is a valuable crop for both subsistence and commercial farming. Its benefits include:Nutrition: The seeds are a good source of protein, essential amino acids, vitamins (particularly B vitamins), and minerals (iron, potassium, and magnesium).Soil Improvement: Pigeon pea is used as a cover crop and in crop rotation to improve soil fertility due to its ability to fix atmospheric nitrogen.Livestock Feed: The plant provides fodder for livestock.Income Generation: It serves as a source of income for farmers through the sale of seeds.Cultural Significance: Pigeon pea is an integral part of the cuisines and cultures in many regions where it is grown.
</string>
    <string name="se8">Pigeon pea is generally considered safe when consumed as a food. However, there are some potential side effects to be aware of:Flatulence: Pigeon pea can cause gas and bloating in some individuals, especially if consumed in large quantities.Allergies: Rarely, individuals may experience allergic reactions to pigeon pea.It\'s important to note that while pigeon pea has many potential health benefits, it should not be used as a replacement for any prescribed medications or treatments for medical conditions. Always consult with a healthcare professional before incorporating new foods or herbs into your diet for medicinal purposes.</string>


    <string name="p9">Calotropis procera</string>
    <string name="s9">Calotropis procera.</string>
    <string name="l9">Ankdo</string>
    <string name="f9">Aclepiadaceae</string>
    <string name="d9">Calotropis procera is a perennial shrub that can grow up to 4 meters in height. It is characterized by its grayish-green leaves and attractive clusters of star-shaped, waxy flowers. The plant has thick, fleshy stems and leaves that are covered in fine hairs, giving them a soft, velvety texture. The fruit of the plant is a large, inflated, and woody capsule, which contains numerous seeds embedded in silky fibers. These fibers are often used for various purposes.</string>
    <string name="dt9">Calotropis procera is native to a wide range of regions, including parts of Africa, the Middle East, and South Asia. It thrives in arid and semi-arid environments and is often found in dry wastelands, along roadsides, and in disturbed areas. It has become naturalized in some parts of Australia and the Americas.</string>
    <string name="m9">Calotropis procera has a long history of medicinal use in traditional systems of medicine. Some of its medicinal uses include:Pain Relief: The latex of the plant is applied topically to relieve pain, particularly in cases of rheumatism and joint pain.Anti-Inflammatory: The plant has anti-inflammatory properties and is used to reduce inflammation and swelling.Wound Healing: The latex is also used as a wound dressing to promote the healing of cuts and sores.Respiratory Conditions: In some regions, it is used to treat respiratory conditions like asthma and bronchitis.Antimalarial: Calotropis procera extracts have been investigated for their potential antimalarial properties.Laxative: In controlled doses, it has been used as a laxative to relieve constipation.Antimicrobial: The plant\'s extracts have shown antimicrobial activity against certain bacteria and fungi.</string>
    <string name="b9">Calotropis procera offers several benefits, including: Soil Stabilization: Its deep roots help prevent soil erosion in arid and semi-arid regions.Fiber Production: The silky fibers surrounding the seeds are used for making ropes, fishing nets, and stuffing pillows and cushions.Ornamental Use: The attractive flowers make it a potential ornamental plant in gardens and landscapes.</string>
    <string name="se9">While Calotropis procera has medicinal uses, it should be used cautiously and under the guidance of a qualified practitioner. Some considerations include:Toxicity: The plant contains toxic compounds, including cardiac glycosides, alkaloids, and latex that can be harmful if ingested in large quantities. It should not be ingested without proper processing and precautions.Skin Irritation: The latex can cause skin irritation and allergic reactions in some individuals.Pregnancy: Pregnant and nursing women should avoid using products containing Calotropis procera as they may have adverse effects on pregnancy and lactation.</string>


    <string name="p10">cannabis sativa</string>
    <string name="l10">Bhang</string>
    <string name="s10">Cannabis sativa</string>
    <string name="f10">Cannabaceae</string>
    <string name="d10">Cannabis sativa is a dioecious (having separate male and female plants) annual plant that has been cultivated for various purposes for thousands of years. It is known for its tall, fibrous stalks and palmate leaves with serrated edges. The plant produces small, inconspicuous flowers that are either male or female. The female flowers, in particular, are rich in cannabinoids.</string>
    <string name="dt10">Cannabis sativa is native to Central Asia but is now widely cultivated and distributed throughout the world, both for industrial hemp and recreational/medicinal marijuana. It can grow in a variety of climates, from temperate to tropical regions.</string>
    <string name="m10">Cannabis sativa has a long history of medicinal use, and it contains various compounds that have potential therapeutic effects. Some of the medicinal uses include:Pain Management: Cannabis is known for its analgesic properties and is used to relieve pain, including chronic pain conditions.Nausea and Vomiting: It can help alleviate nausea and vomiting, often used in cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy.Appetite Stimulation: Cannabis can stimulate appetite, making it useful for individuals with appetite loss or wasting syndrome.Seizure Disorders: Some forms of cannabis, such as CBD (cannabidiol), have shown promise in reducing the frequency and severity of seizures in epilepsy.Anxiety and Stress: In some cases, cannabis may provide relief from anxiety and stress, although individual responses can vary.Glaucoma: Cannabis may help lower intraocular pressure in glaucoma patients.Inflammatory Conditions: It may be used to manage inflammatory conditions like arthritis.Sleep Disorders: Some individuals find cannabis helpful for improving sleep quality.</string>
    <string name="b10">The benefits of Cannabis sativa primarily revolve around its potential to alleviate symptoms and improve the quality of life for individuals with various medical conditions. These benefits are largely attributed to its cannabinoids, such as THC (tetrahydrocannabinol) and CBD (cannabidiol), which interact with the endocannabinoid system in the body.</string>
    <string name="se10">Cannabis use can have side effects, including impaired coordination, memory, and judgment.Frequent and heavy use of THC-rich cannabis can lead to addiction and withdrawal symptoms.Smoking cannabis may harm lung health and may increase the risk of lung-related conditions.There is a risk of mental health effects, such as anxiety, paranoia, and an increased risk of psychosis, particularly with high-THC strains.Cannabis can impair cognitive function and should not be used when activities like driving or operating heavy machinery are required.</string>

    <string name="p11">capsicum annuum</string>
    <string name="l11">Marchi</string>
    <string name="s11">Capsicum annuum</string>
    <string name="f11">Solanaceae</string>
    <string name="d11">Capsicum annuum is a species of flowering plant in the Solanaceae family. It is known for its edible peppers, which come in various shapes, sizes, and colors, ranging from green, yellow, orange, and red. The plant is typically an annual or perennial depending on the climate and variety. It has dark green leaves and produces small, white flowers with five petals. The fruit of Capsicum annuum can be either mild or hot, depending on the specific variety and its level of capsaicin content.</string>
    <string name="dt11">Capsicum annuum is native to the Americas, with a long history of cultivation in Central and South America. It is now widely cultivated and distributed worldwide, making it a staple in many cuisines. It is grown in various climates, including tropical, subtropical, and temperate regions.</string>
    <string name="m11">While Capsicum annuum is primarily known for its culinary uses, it also has some medicinal applications, often related to its active compound, capsaicin. Medicinal uses may include:Pain Relief: Topical creams and ointments containing capsaicin are used for pain relief, particularly for conditions like osteoarthritis, neuropathic pain, and muscle pain. Capsaicin works by desensitizing pain receptors.Weight Management: Capsaicin is believed to increase metabolism and may aid in weight management by promoting fat oxidation.Digestive Health: Some people use mild forms of Capsicum annuum to stimulate digestion, improve appetite, and alleviate mild gastrointestinal discomfort.</string>
    <string name="b11">Capsicum annuum offers several health benefits, primarily due to the presence of capsaicin and other compounds. Some of the potential benefits include:Rich in Vitamins: Peppers are a good source of vitamins, particularly vitamin C, which is essential for immune function and skin health.Antioxidant Properties: Peppers contain antioxidants that help combat free radicals, potentially reducing the risk of chronic diseases.Pain Relief: Topical capsaicin can provide pain relief for certain conditions.Weight Management: Capsaicin may aid in weight management and fat loss.Heart Health: Some research suggests that consuming Capsicum annuum may have a positive impact on cardiovascular health.</string>
    <string name="se11">While Capsicum annuum is generally safe for consumption, there are some potential side effects to be aware of:Digestive Discomfort: Consuming hot peppers with a high capsaicin content can cause digestive discomfort, including stomach pain and diarrhea in sensitive individuals.Irritation: Capsaicin can cause skin and eye irritation. Handling hot peppers or their seeds without proper protection can lead to skin burns or eye irritation. Washing hands thoroughly after handling peppers is advisable.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to peppers and may experience allergic reactions such as itching, hives, or swelling.Interaction with Medications: If you are taking medications or have underlying health conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before consuming Capsicum annuum, particularly in large quantities or as a supplement.It\'s important to note that the level of spiciness or heat in Capsicum annuum peppers varies widely among different varieties, so individuals can choose peppers that suit their taste preferences and tolerance for spiciness. Additionally, moderation is key when incorporating hot peppers into your diet to avoid potential digestive discomfort.</string>

    <string name="p12">carica papaya</string>
    <string name="l12">Papaya</string>
    <string name="s12">Carica papaya</string>
    <string name="f12">Caricaceae</string>
    <string name="d12">Carica papaya is a tropical fruit tree that is widely cultivated for its sweet and nutritious fruit. The tree typically grows to a height of 5 to 10 meters (16 to 33 feet) and has a single stem or trunk. The leaves are large and deeply lobed, and the fruit is typically elongated and can vary in size from small to large, depending on the variety. Papaya fruit is usually green when unripe and turns yellow or orange as it ripens. The flesh of ripe papaya is orange or pinkish and contains numerous small, black seeds that are edible but are often discarded.</string>
    <string name="dt12">Carica papaya is native to tropical regions of the Americas, particularly southern Mexico and Central America. It is now widely cultivated in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide, including Southeast Asia, the Caribbean, Africa, and many other parts of the world.</string>
    <string name="m12">Papaya has a long history of medicinal use in traditional medicine systems, and various parts of the plant are utilized for their potential health benefits:Digestive Health: Papaya contains enzymes like papain, which aid in digestion and can be helpful for individuals with digestive problems. It is often used to alleviate symptoms of indigestion and constipation.Wound Healing: Papain, when applied topically, may assist in wound healing by breaking down dead tissue and promoting cell growth.Anti-Inflammatory: Papaya is known for its anti-inflammatory properties and may be used to reduce inflammation and pain associated with conditions like arthritis.Skin Health: Some people use papaya extracts or pulp topically to improve skin health and treat conditions like acne and sunburn.</string>
    <string name="b12">Papaya offers several health benefits, primarily due to its rich nutrient profile. Some potential benefits include:Rich in Vitamins and Minerals: Papaya is a good source of vitamin C, vitamin A (in the form of beta-carotene), and various B vitamins. It also contains minerals like potassium and magnesium.Digestive Aid: The enzymes in papaya, particularly papain, can aid in digestion and alleviate digestive discomfort.Antioxidant Properties: Papaya is rich in antioxidants, which can help combat free radicals and reduce the risk of chronic diseases.Immune Support: The high vitamin C content in papaya supports the immune system.Skin Health: Topical application of papaya may improve skin health and alleviate skin issues.</string>
    <string name="se12">While papaya is generally considered safe when consumed in moderation, some individuals may experience mild side effects, including:Allergic Reactions: In rare cases, individuals may be allergic to papaya and may experience allergic reactions such as itching, hives, or swelling.Stomach Upset: Consuming excessive amounts of papaya may lead to digestive discomfort, including diarrhea.Latex Allergy: Some individuals with latex allergies may also be sensitive to papaya, as the latex in papaya may trigger an allergic response.Unripe Papaya: Consuming unripe papaya, particularly during pregnancy, is not recommended, as it contains higher levels of latex and papain, which can have adverse effects.It\'s important to consume papaya in moderation as part of a balanced diet to avoid potential side effects. If you have specific health concerns or conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before making significant dietary changes or using papaya for medicinal purposes.</string>

    <string name="p13">celastrus paniculata</string>
    <string name="l13">Malkankni</string>
    <string name="s13">Celastrus paniculata</string>
    <string name="f13">Celastraceae</string>
    <string name="d13">Celastrus paniculata is a woody climbing shrub or vine native to the Indian subcontinent and Southeast Asia. It is known for its distinctive red fruits and aromatic seeds. The plant has slender stems with elliptical leaves that are green on the upper surface and grayish-white on the lower surface. The small, red or orange fruits are produced in clusters and contain seeds. The seeds are the most valuable part of the plant and are used for their medicinal properties.</string>
    <string name="dt13">Celastrus paniculata is native to the Indian subcontinent, including India, Nepal, and Bhutan. It is also found in parts of Southeast Asia, including Thailand and Indonesia. It prefers subtropical and tropical climates.</string>
    <string name="m13">Celastrus paniculata has a long history of use in traditional Ayurvedic and Siddha medicine systems. The seeds and oil derived from them are the most commonly used parts and are known for their potential medicinal properties:Memory Enhancement: Celastrus paniculata is often used as a memory enhancer and cognitive tonic. It is believed to improve concentration, learning, and overall mental alertness.Stress and Anxiety: The plant is used to reduce stress, anxiety, and mental fatigue. It may have adaptogenic properties that help the body cope with stress.Anti-inflammatory: It is believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and may be used for conditions associated with inflammation.Pain Relief: Some traditional uses include using Celastrus paniculata for pain relief, including headaches and joint pain.Neurological Disorders: It is used in traditional medicine to manage certain neurological conditions.</string>
    <string name="b13">Celastrus paniculata is primarily valued for its potential cognitive and mental health benefits. Some of the benefits attributed to it include:Improved Memory and Concentration: It is believed to enhance memory and concentration, making it popular among students and individuals seeking cognitive enhancement.Stress Reduction: Celastrus paniculata may help reduce stress and anxiety, promoting a sense of well-being.Anti-inflammatory Effects: Some studies suggest that it may have anti-inflammatory effects, which can be beneficial for various health conditions.</string>
    <string name="se13">Celastrus paniculata is generally considered safe when used at recommended doses. However, excessive consumption or misuse may lead to side effects such as:Gastrointestinal Upset: Some individuals may experience stomach discomfort or digestive issues when using Celastrus paniculata.Allergic Reactions: Allergic reactions are possible but relatively rare. If you experience itching, rash, swelling, or difficulty breathing after using it, seek medical attention immediately.Interaction with Medications: If you are taking medications or have underlying health conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before using Celastrus paniculata, as it may interact with certain medications.It\'s important to note that while Celastrus paniculata has a history of traditional use, scientific research on its efficacy and safety is ongoing. If you are considering using it for medicinal purposes, it is advisable to consult with a qualified Ayurvedic practitioner or healthcare provider who can provide guidance on proper usage and dosage based on your specific needs and health conditions.</string>


    <string name="p14">centella asiatica</string>
    <string name="l14">Brahmi</string>
    <string name="f14">Apiaceae</string>
    <string name="s14">Centella asiatica</string>
    <string name="d14">Centella asiatica is a small, herbaceous plant that is native to various regions of Asia, including India, China, Indonesia, and other Southeast Asian countries. It is known for its low-growing, creeping habit and distinctive round or kidney-shaped leaves with scalloped edges. The leaves and stems of Centella asiatica are green and contain bioactive compounds that have been used for their potential medicinal properties.</string>
    <string name="dt14">Centella asiatica is native to a wide range of Asian countries, and it thrives in tropical and subtropical regions. It can often be found in wetlands, along the edges of streams, and in damp soil. Due to its valuable medicinal properties, it is also cultivated in various parts of the world.</string>
    <string name="m14">Centella asiatica has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine. The aerial parts of the plant, particularly the leaves, are used for their potential medicinal benefits:Cognitive Function: Centella asiatica is often used to enhance cognitive function, memory, and mental clarity. It is believed to have adaptogenic properties that can help reduce mental fatigue and improve concentration.Wound Healing: It is used topically to promote wound healing and reduce the appearance of scars. Centella asiatica extracts are found in various skincare products.Anti-inflammatory: The plant is known for its anti-inflammatory properties and may be used to manage inflammatory conditions, such as arthritis or skin inflammation.Antioxidant: Centella asiatica contains antioxidants that help protect cells from oxidative damage caused by free radicals.Circulatory Health: Some traditional uses include its potential to improve blood circulation and reduce venous insufficiency symptoms.</string>
    <string name="b14">Centella asiatica offers several potential health benefits, primarily related to cognitive function, wound healing, and its anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties:Cognitive Enhancement: It is believed to improve memory, concentration, and overall cognitive function, making it popular among students and individuals seeking mental clarity.Wound Healing: Topical application of Centella asiatica can help accelerate wound healing and reduce the appearance of scars.Anti-Inflammatory: It may assist in managing inflammatory conditions and reducing inflammation-related discomfort.Antioxidant Effects: The plant\'s antioxidants contribute to overall health and may help prevent cellular damage.</string>
    <string name="se14">Centella asiatica is generally considered safe when used in moderate amounts for short durations. However, some individuals may experience mild side effects, including stomach upset, headache, or skin irritation when applied topically.Excessive consumption or use may lead to side effects, such as liver damage, photosensitivity, and allergic reactions in rare cases.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use it with caution, and it is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using it medicinally.</string>

    <string name="p15">cinnamomun camphora</string>
    <string name="l15">Kapur</string>
    <string name="f15">Lauraceae</string>
    <string name="s15">Cinnamomum camphora</string>
    <string name="d15">Cinnamomum camphora is a large evergreen tree native to East Asia, including countries like China, Japan, and Taiwan. It is known for its distinctive camphor-scented leaves, wood, and crystalline camphor compound extracted from its bark and wood. The tree typically reaches heights of 15 to 50 meters (49 to 164 feet) and has an upright growth habit. The leaves are glossy, ovate-lanceolate, and aromatic when crushed. The wood is valued for its fragrance and is used in the production of camphor oil.</string>
    <string name="dt15">Cinnamomum camphora is native to East Asia but has been introduced and cultivated in various parts of the world, including India, Sri Lanka, and several regions with tropical and subtropical climates. It thrives in well-drained soils and warm, humid conditions.</string>
    <string name="m15">Cinnamomum camphora has a history of traditional medicinal use in various cultures. The key medicinal component is camphor, which is extracted from the wood, bark, and leaves of the tree. Medicinal uses of camphor and Cinnamomum camphora include:Respiratory Relief: Camphor is used topically or in steam inhalation for its decongestant properties. It can help relieve nasal congestion, cough, and respiratory discomfort.Pain Relief: Camphor is used in topical products such as balms and creams to alleviate minor aches and pains, including muscle and joint pain.Anti-inflammatory: Camphor may have anti-inflammatory properties and is sometimes used for soothing skin conditions like itching or irritation.Mental Clarity: In some traditional practices, camphor is believed to have a stimulating effect on the mind and is used to enhance mental clarity and alertness.Aromatherapy: The aroma of camphor is used in aromatherapy for its stimulating and invigorating scent.</string>
    <string name="b15">Cinnamomum camphora provides several potential benefits, primarily through the use of camphor:Respiratory Relief: Camphor can help alleviate respiratory congestion and discomfort, making it a common ingredient in chest rubs and inhalation products.Pain Relief: Topical camphor preparations can provide temporary relief from minor pains and muscle soreness.Anti-inflammatory Effects: Camphor may have mild anti-inflammatory properties when applied topically to the skin.Aromatic Benefits: The aromatic properties of camphor are used for their invigorating and stimulating effects, both in aromatherapy and traditional practices.</string>
    <string name="se15">Side Effects:While camphor and Cinnamomum camphora can be beneficial, it\'s important to use them with caution and adhere to recommended guidelines, as excessive use or misuse can lead to side effects:Skin Irritation: Topical application of camphor can cause skin irritation or allergic reactions in some individuals, especially if applied in high concentrations.Oral Toxicity: Ingesting camphor can be toxic and lead to symptoms such as nausea, vomiting, headache, confusion, and seizures. In severe cases, it can be life-threatening. Camphor should never be ingested.Respiratory Issues: Inhaling high concentrations of camphor vapor can be harmful, leading to respiratory distress. Steam inhalation with camphor should be done with caution and under supervision.Children and Pregnant Women: Camphor products should be kept out of reach of children, as even small amounts can be toxic to them. Pregnant and breastfeeding women should avoid using camphor products.Camphor products should be used sparingly and in accordance with product labeling and safety recommendations. It\'s crucial to consult with a healthcare professional if you have specific health concerns or conditions, especially when using camphor products, and to seek immediate medical attention in case of accidental ingestion or severe adverse reactions.</string>


    <string name="p16">Cinnamomum verum</string>
    <string name="l16">Taj</string>
    <string name="f16">Lauraceae</string>
    <string name="s16">Cinnamomum verum</string>
    <string name="d16">Cinnamomum verum is a small to medium-sized tree that can reach heights of 10-15 meters (30-50 feet). It has oval-shaped leaves that are dark green on the upper surface and lighter green underneath. The tree\'s bark is light brown and papery, which is harvested for its aromatic inner layer. Ceylon cinnamon produces small yellowish-white flowers that develop into oval-shaped berries.</string>
    <string name="dt16">Ceylon cinnamon is native to Sri Lanka and is also cultivated in other tropical regions, including India, Madagascar, Seychelles, and the Caribbean. Sri Lanka, however, remains the primary producer and exporter of true cinnamon.</string>
    <string name="m16">Ceylon cinnamon has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine. It is valued for its potential health benefits, which include:Digestive Aid: Cinnamon is known for its carminative properties, which can help relieve digestive discomfort, including gas and bloating. It may also help with indigestion and heartburn.Anti-Inflammatory: Cinnamaldehyde, a compound found in cinnamon, has anti-inflammatory properties that may be beneficial for reducing inflammation in the body.Antioxidant: Cinnamon is rich in antioxidants, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage caused by free radicals. This may contribute to its potential anti-aging effects.Blood Sugar Regulation: Some studies suggest that cinnamon may help regulate blood sugar levels by improving insulin sensitivity, making it potentially useful for individuals with type 2 diabetes.Antimicrobial: Cinnamaldehyde and other compounds in cinnamon have antimicrobial properties, which may help fight infections and inhibit the growth of bacteria and fungi.</string>
    <string name="b16">Ceylon cinnamon is prized for its sweet and delicate flavor, making it a popular spice for culinary purposes. It is often used in baking, desserts, and as a flavor enhancer in various dishes.The spice is a natural food preservative due to its antimicrobial properties.Cinnamon is used in perfumes and aromatherapy for its pleasant fragrance.Its potential health benefits make it a valuable addition to herbal remedies and dietary supplements.</string>
    <string name="se16">When used in moderation as a spice, Ceylon cinnamon is generally safe for most people. However, excessive consumption of cinnamon supplements or essential oil can lead to side effects such as:Allergic reactions in some individuals.Liver toxicity when consumed in large quantities.Blood-thinning effects, which may be problematic for those taking blood-thinning medications.Interaction with certain medications, especially those for diabetes and blood pressure. It\'s important to consult a healthcare professional if you\'re considering using cinnamon as a supplement, especially in medicinal doses.Overall, Cinnamomum verum, or Ceylon cinnamon, is a versatile spice with potential health benefits and a rich cultural history in traditional medicine and culinary traditions. It should be consumed in moderation as part of a balanced diet and used cautiously in supplement form, especially in medicinal applications. Always consult with a healthcare provider before using it for specific health purposes, especially if you have underlying health conditions or are taking medications.</string>


    <string name="p17">citrullus colocynthis</string>
    <string name="l17">Indravarna</string>
    <string name="f17">Cucurbitaceae</string>
    <string name="s17">Citrullus colocynthis</string>
    <string name="d17">Citrullus colocynthis is a wild, perennial, and herbaceous plant native to the Mediterranean region, parts of Africa, and South Asia. It is a vining plant that typically grows in arid and semi-arid regions. The plant produces small, round or oblong fruits that resemble miniature watermelons but are extremely bitter in taste. The leaves of Citrullus colocynthis are lobed and have a rough texture.</string>
    <string name="dt17">Citrullus colocynthis is primarily found in arid and semi-arid regions of the Mediterranean, North Africa, the Middle East, and parts of South Asia. It is adapted to thrive in hot and dry climates.</string>
    <string name="m17">Citrullus colocynthis has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Arabic medicine. Various parts of the plant, including the fruit pulp and seeds, have been used for their potential medicinal properties. However, it\'s important to note that the plant is highly toxic and must be used with extreme caution.Laxative: The pulp of Citrullus colocynthis has been used as a strong laxative, although it can be highly irritating to the digestive system.Anti-inflammatory: The plant has been used to reduce inflammation in traditional medicine practices.Diabetes Management: Some traditional systems have used Citrullus colocynthis to help manage diabetes, although this use is controversial due to its toxicity.Antimicrobial: It has been explored for its potential antimicrobial properties.</string>
    <string name="b17">While Citrullus colocynthis has been used for various purposes in traditional medicine, its extreme bitterness and toxicity make it a risky choice for self-medication. Its use should be strictly supervised by qualified healthcare professionals, and safer alternatives are available for most medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="se17">Citrullus colocynthis is considered highly toxic and should be used with extreme caution. The plant and its extracts can cause severe adverse effects, including:Gastrointestinal Irritation: Ingesting even small amounts of Citrullus colocynthis can lead to severe digestive distress, including nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, and abdominal pain.Toxicity: The plant contains cucurbitacins, highly toxic compounds that can cause poisoning. Ingesting Citrullus colocynthis can lead to serious health issues, including liver and kidney damage, cardiovascular problems, and even death.Skin Irritation: Contact with the plant\'s sap or skin can cause skin irritation and dermatitis.Interaction with Medications: Citrullus colocynthis can interact with medications and exacerbate their effects, potentially leading to dangerous outcomes.Due to its high toxicity and potential for severe side effects, Citrullus colocynthis is not recommended for self-medication or home remedies. If you have any health concerns or are seeking treatments for specific conditions, it is crucial to consult with a qualified healthcare provider who can provide safe and effective alternatives.</string>


    <string name="p18">citrus limon</string>
    <string name="l18">Limbu</string>
    <string name="f18">Rutaceae</string>
    <string name="s18">Citrus Limon</string>
    <string name="d18">Lemon is a small, evergreen tree or shrub with distinctive glossy, oval leaves. The fruit it bears is the lemon, which is typically yellow when ripe and oval or elliptical in shape. Lemons are known for their bright yellow color and sour taste. The fruit is juicy and contains numerous small seeds, which are often discarded when consuming the juice or pulp. Lemon trees also produce fragrant white flowers.</string>
    <string name="dt18">Lemon is believed to have originated in Southeast Asia, particularly in regions of India, Myanmar (Burma), and China. It is now widely cultivated in subtropical and tropical regions around the world. Lemons thrive in warm climates and are grown in countries such as India, China, Mexico, the United States, Italy, and Spain.</string>
    <string name="m18">Lemon has a long history of medicinal use, and various parts of the fruit, including the juice, pulp, and peel, are utilized for their potential health benefits. Some of the medicinal uses of lemon include:Vitamin C: Lemons are a rich source of vitamin C, which is essential for a healthy immune system and can help prevent scurvy.Digestive Health: Lemon juice can aid digestion and relieve indigestion and constipation. It is also used as a natural remedy for heartburn and bloating.Skin Care: Lemon juice is sometimes used topically to lighten skin, reduce acne, and improve overall skin health.Antioxidant Properties: The antioxidants in lemon may help combat free radicals and reduce the risk of chronic diseases.Weight Management: Some people use lemon water as a weight loss aid, as it can help promote hydration and reduce calorie intake when substituted for sugary drinks.Oral Health: Lemon juice can be used as a natural mouthwash to freshen breath and prevent gum problems.Respiratory Health: Inhaling the aroma of lemon essential oil may help clear nasal passages and relieve symptoms of congestion.</string>
    <string name="b18">Lemon offers several potential health benefits, primarily due to its high vitamin C content and antioxidants. Some of the benefits include:Immune Support: The vitamin C in lemon helps boost the immune system and protect against infections.Antioxidant Protection: Lemon\'s antioxidants may reduce oxidative stress and lower the risk of chronic diseases.Digestive Aid: Lemon can aid in digestion and promote regular bowel movements.Hydration: Lemon water is a refreshing and hydrating beverage.Skin Health: Topical use of lemon juice may improve skin tone and reduce acne.</string>
    <string name="se18">While lemon is generally considered safe for consumption and topical use, there are a few potential side effects to be aware of:Tooth Erosion: The high acidity of lemon juice can erode tooth enamel over time. It\'s advisable to rinse your mouth with water after consuming lemon juice and to avoid brushing your teeth immediately after to protect your enamel.Skin Sensitivity: Lemon juice can cause skin irritation, especially when applied to sensitive or damaged skin. Diluting lemon juice with water is recommended for topical use.Gastroesophageal Reflux: Lemon juice can trigger or worsen symptoms of acid reflux or heartburn in some individuals.Individual reactions to lemon may vary, and it\'s important to use it in moderation and be mindful of any adverse effects. If you have specific health concerns or medical conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before making significant dietary or topical changes involving lemon.</string>

    <string name="p19">clerodendrum phlomidis </string>
    <string name="l19">Arani</string>
    <string name="f19">Verbenaceae</string>
    <string name="s19">Clerodendrum phlomidis</string>
    <string name="d19">Clerodendrum phlomidis is a medicinal plant native to India and other parts of South Asia. It is a small shrub that typically grows to a height of 2 to 3 meters (6.6 to 9.8 feet). The plant has a woody stem and branches covered with small, green leaves that are opposite and elliptical in shape. The flowers of Clerodendrum phlomidis are tubular and white or pale lavender in color. The plant produces small, spherical fruits.</string>
    <string name="dt19">Clerodendrum phlomidis is primarily found in India, where it is native to various regions, including the Western Ghats and parts of the Deccan Plateau. It thrives in tropical and subtropical climates and is also found in other parts of South Asia.</string>
    <string name="m19">Clerodendrum phlomidis has a long history of use in traditional Ayurvedic and Siddha medicine systems. Various parts of the plant, including the roots, leaves, and flowers, are used for their potential medicinal properties:Respiratory Health: Clerodendrum phlomidis is often used to treat respiratory conditions, including coughs, colds, and bronchitis. It is believed to have bronchodilatory and expectorant effects.Anti-inflammatory: The plant is used for its anti-inflammatory properties and may be applied topically or consumed internally to alleviate inflammation-related conditions.Antipyretic: It is used to reduce fever and is sometimes employed as an antipyretic agent.Immunomodulatory: Some traditional uses involve using Clerodendrum phlomidis to boost the immune system and improve overall health.</string>
    <string name="b19">Clerodendrum phlomidis offers several potential health benefits, primarily related to its use in traditional medicine:Respiratory Support: It is used to relieve respiratory discomfort, such as cough and bronchitis.Anti-inflammatory: Clerodendrum phlomidis may help reduce inflammation and alleviate related symptoms.Fever Reduction: It is used to lower fever and reduce fever-related symptoms.mmune Boosting: Some traditional practices use it to enhance immune function.</string>
    <string name="se19">While Clerodendrum phlomidis is generally considered safe when used in traditional medicinal practices and culinary uses, it is essential to exercise caution and consult with a qualified healthcare provider, particularly when using it for therapeutic purposes. Some considerations include:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to components of the plant, and allergic reactions are possible.Interaction with Medications: If you are taking medications or have underlying health conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before using Clerodendrum phlomidis, as it may interact with certain medications.Pregnancy and Lactation: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider before using any herbal remedies, including Clerodendrum phlomidis.As with any herbal remedy, it is advisable to seek guidance from a qualified herbalist, Ayurvedic practitioner, or healthcare provider who can provide personalized advice on the proper usage and dosage of Clerodendrum phlomidis based on your specific health needs and conditions.</string>


    <string name="p20">cocos nucifera</string>
    <string name="l20">Nariel</string>
    <string name="f20">Arecaceae</string>
    <string name="s20">Cocos nucifera</string>
    <string name="d20">Cocos nucifera, or the coconut palm, is a tall, slender, and tropical palm tree known for its iconic and versatile fruit—the coconut. The tree typically reaches heights of 15 to 30 meters (49 to 98 feet) and has a straight, unbranched trunk with large, feathery fronds at the top. Coconuts are drupes, and they have a hard, fibrous outer husk, a woody shell, and a rich, white, edible flesh inside. The interior also contains coconut water, a refreshing and nutritious liquid.</string>
    <string name="dt20">The coconut palm is native to coastal regions of tropical and subtropical areas, including parts of Southeast Asia, the Indian subcontinent, the Pacific Islands, and parts of Africa. It has been cultivated and introduced to many other tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.</string>
    <string name="m20">The various parts of the coconut palm have been used for their potential medicinal properties in traditional medicine systems in many cultures. Some of the medicinal uses of Cocos nucifera include:Digestive Health: Coconut water is sometimes consumed to relieve indigestion and soothe upset stomachs.Hydration: Coconut water is a natural electrolyte-rich beverage and is often used for rehydration, especially in hot and tropical climates.Laxative: Coconut oil, when ingested in small quantities, can act as a mild laxative, aiding in digestion and promoting regular bowel movements.Skin Health: Coconut oil is used topically to moisturize the skin, treat dryness, and alleviate conditions like eczema. It may also promote wound healing and reduce the appearance of scars.Hair Care: Coconut oil is popularly used in hair treatments to condition and strengthen hair, reduce frizz, and promote healthy scalp and hair growth.Antimicrobial: Coconut oil contains compounds like lauric acid, which have antimicrobial properties and can be used for skin and oral health.</string>
    <string name="b20">Cocos nucifera offers a wide range of potential health and wellness benefits:Hydration: Coconut water is a natural and refreshing way to stay hydrated, thanks to its electrolyte content.Nutrient-Rich: Coconut flesh and water are rich in essential nutrients, including vitamins, minerals, and healthy fats.Digestive Aid: The fiber content in coconut may support digestive health.Skin and Hair Care: Coconut oil is a versatile natural product for skincare and haircare, moisturizing and nourishing the skin and hair.Antioxidant Properties: Coconut oil and other coconut products contain antioxidants that may help combat free radicals.</string>
    <string name="se20">While Cocos nucifera is generally considered safe for consumption and topical use, it\'s important to be aware of potential side effects:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to coconut or its derivatives. Allergic reactions can range from mild skin irritation to more severe symptoms.Gastrointestinal Distress: Excessive consumption of coconut products, especially oil, can lead to digestive discomfort, including diarrhea.High Calorie Content: Coconut products, particularly coconut oil and coconut milk, are calorie-dense, and overconsumption can contribute to weight gain if not used in moderation.Skin Sensitivity: While coconut oil is well-tolerated by most people, some individuals with sensitive skin may experience irritation. It\'s advisable to do a patch test before applying coconut oil to a larger area of the skin.As with any natural remedy or food, moderation is key, and individual reactions can vary. If you have specific health concerns or conditions, consult with a healthcare provider before making significant dietary or topical changes involving coconut products.</string>


    <string name="p21">commiphora wightii</string>
    <string name="l21">Gugal</string>
    <string name="f21">Burseraceae</string>
    <string name="s21">Commiphora wightii</string>
    <string name="d21">Commiphora wightii is a small to medium-sized deciduous tree or shrub native to India, particularly in the arid and semi-arid regions of Rajasthan, Gujarat, and some parts of Pakistan. The tree has a knotted, gnarled trunk and pinnate leaves that are divided into leaflets. It produces small, fragrant flowers and bears fruit that contains a resinous gum known for its medicinal properties. The gum resin is typically collected from incisions made in the bark of the tree.</string>
    <string name="dt21">Commiphora wightii is primarily found in the arid and semi-arid regions of India and Pakistan. It is well adapted to grow in hot and dry climates and thrives in rocky and sandy soils.</string>
    <string name="m21">Commiphora wightii has been used for centuries in traditional Ayurvedic medicine for its therapeutic properties. The gum resin obtained from the tree, known as "guggul" or "guggulu," is the most well-known and widely used part of the plant. Some of the medicinal uses of Commiphora wightii include:Cholesterol Management: Guggul is traditionally used to help lower elevated levels of LDL (low-density lipoprotein) cholesterol and triglycerides in the blood, making it potentially beneficial for heart health.Anti-inflammatory: Guggul has anti-inflammatory properties and is used to manage various inflammatory conditions, including arthritis.Weight Management: It is believed to aid in weight management by supporting metabolism and promoting fat loss.Thyroid Health: Guggul is used in Ayurveda to support thyroid function and manage conditions like hypothyroidism.Antioxidant: It has antioxidant properties that may help protect cells from oxidative stress.Anti-Arthritic: Guggul may help alleviate symptoms of arthritis, such as joint pain and inflammation.</string>
    <string name="b21">Commiphora wightii offers several potential health benefits, primarily attributed to the gum resin guggul:Cholesterol Reduction: Guggul may help lower LDL cholesterol and triglyceride levels, which can contribute to better cardiovascular health.Anti-inflammatory: It has been used to manage various inflammatory conditions, providing relief from pain and discomfort.Weight Management: Some studies suggest that guggul may support weight loss efforts by promoting fat metabolism.Thyroid Support: In Ayurveda, it is used to balance thyroid function, especially in cases of hypothyroidism.Antioxidant Effects: Guggul\'s antioxidants help protect cells from oxidative damage and support overall health.</string>
    <string name="se21">Guggul is generally considered safe when used in appropriate doses for short durations. However, some people may experience side effects, including stomach upset, diarrhea, or skin rashes.It can interact with certain medications, so it\'s essential to consult a healthcare professional before using guggul supplements, especially if you are on medication for cholesterol or other health conditions.Prolonged use of high doses may lead to liver toxicity, so it should not be used indiscriminately or for extended periods without medical supervision.</string>

    <string name="p22">coriandrum sativum</string>
    <string name="l22">Dhana</string>
    <string name="f22">Apiaceae</string>
    <string name="s22">Coriandrum sativum</string>
    <string name="d22">Coriandrum sativum is an annual herb that belongs to the parsley family. It is well-known for its dual use, as both the fresh leaves (cilantro) and the dried seeds (coriander seeds) are widely used in culinary preparations. The plant typically grows to a height of 50 to 70 centimeters (20 to 28 inches) and has delicate, feathery leaves. The flowers of coriander are small, white or pale pink, and are arranged in umbrella-like clusters. The seeds are spherical, light brown, and have a citrusy, earthy aroma.</string>
    <string name="dt22">Coriandrum sativum is native to the Mediterranean region and has been cultivated and naturalized in many parts of the world. It is grown in various climates and is a common herb in many cuisines, especially in Asian, Middle Eastern, and Latin American dishes.</string>
    <string name="m22">Coriandrum sativum has a history of medicinal use in traditional healing systems, including Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine. Some of the medicinal uses of coriander include:Digestive Aid: Coriander seeds are known for their carminative properties, helping to relieve digestive discomfort, bloating, and gas.Anti-inflammatory: Coriander may have anti-inflammatory effects and can be used to alleviate symptoms of inflammatory conditions.Cholesterol Management: Some studies suggest that coriander can help lower cholesterol levels.Antioxidant Properties: Coriander contains antioxidants that can help protect cells from oxidative damage.Mouthwash: The antimicrobial properties of coriander can be used as a natural mouthwash to freshen breath and combat oral bacteria.</string>
    <string name="b22">Coriandrum sativum offers several potential health benefits, both when used as a spice in culinary dishes and in traditional medicine:Digestive Health: Coriander seeds can aid in digestion and reduce gastrointestinal discomfort.Anti-inflammatory: Coriander may help alleviate inflammation-related symptoms.Cholesterol Reduction: It may contribute to lower cholesterol levels.Antioxidant Effects: Coriander\'s antioxidants can support overall health.Oral Health: It is used as a natural remedy to promote oral hygiene and freshen breath.</string>
    <string name="se22">Coriander is generally considered safe for most people when consumed in moderate amounts as part of a balanced diet. However, there are some considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to coriander and may experience skin rashes, itching, or other allergic symptoms.Gastrointestinal Upset: In rare cases, excessive consumption of coriander seeds or leaves may lead to digestive discomfort, including diarrhea or stomach cramps.Potentially Unsafe During Pregnancy: There is some concern that large amounts of coriander might stimulate uterine contractions and lead to a miscarriage. Pregnant women should consume it in moderation, primarily as a culinary herb, and consult with a healthcare provider for guidance.As with any food or natural remedy, individual reactions may vary. If you have specific health concerns, allergies, or medical conditions, it\'s advisable to consult with a healthcare provider or a qualified herbalist before using coriander in therapeutic quantities or for medicinal purposes.</string>


    <string name="p23">costus speciosus</string>
    <string name="l23">Pokramul</string>
    <string name="f23">Costaceae</string>
    <string name="s23">Costus speciosus</string>
    <string name="d23">Costus speciosus is a tropical herbaceous plant characterized by its distinctive, spiral arrangement of leaves around the stem, which gives it the common name "Spiral Ginger." It is not a true ginger but is often referred to as such due to its similar growth habit and appearance. The plant typically reaches a height of 1 to 2 meters (3 to 6 feet). The leaves are long and lance-shaped, with prominent parallel veins. The flowers of Costus speciosus are tubular and red to orange-red in color, emerging from cone-like bracts. It is primarily grown for its ornamental value but also has medicinal uses.</string>
    <string name="dt23">Costus speciosus is native to South Asia, including India, Sri Lanka, and other parts of Southeast Asia. It thrives in tropical and subtropical climates and is also cultivated as an ornamental plant in various other regions around the world.</string>
    <string name="m23">Costus speciosus has a history of traditional medicinal use in Ayurveda, Siddha, and other traditional healing systems in South Asia. Various parts of the plant, including the rhizomes (underground stems) and leaves, are used for their potential medicinal properties. Some of the medicinal uses of Costus speciosus include:Anti-inflammatory: The rhizomes of Costus speciosus are believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and are used to alleviate inflammatory conditions and joint pain.Digestive Health: In traditional medicine, it is used to promote digestive health and ease digestive discomfort.Respiratory Health: Some preparations of Costus speciosus are used to relieve respiratory conditions, such as coughs and asthma.Diuretic: It may act as a diuretic, promoting the excretion of urine and potentially aiding in kidney and urinary health.Wound Healing: In some regions, the paste made from the rhizome is applied topically to promote wound healing.</string>
    <string name="b23">Costus speciosus offers several potential health benefits, primarily attributed to its traditional medicinal uses: Anti-inflammatory: It may help reduce inflammation and relieve inflammatory conditions.Digestive Aid: Costus speciosus can support digestive health and alleviate digestive discomfort.Respiratory Relief: Some preparations may provide relief from respiratory symptoms.Diuretic: It may promote urine production and support urinary health.</string>
    <string name="se23">While Costus speciosus is generally considered safe when used in traditional medicinal practices and culinary uses, there are a few potential considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to components of the plant and could experience allergic reactions.Pregnancy and Lactation: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider before using Costus speciosus supplements or remedies.Gastrointestinal Distress: Excessive consumption of Costus speciosus or its preparations may lead to gastrointestinal discomfort, including stomach upset or diarrhea.As with any herbal remedy, it is advisable to seek guidance from a qualified Ayurvedic practitioner, herbalist, or healthcare provider who can provide personalized advice on the proper usage and dosage of Costus speciosus based on your specific health needs and conditions. Additionally, if you experience any adverse reactions, discontinue use and consult a healthcare professional.</string>

    <string name="p24">cucumis melo</string>
    <string name="l24">Methi</string>
    <string name="f24">Cucurbitaceae</string>
    <string name="s24">cumis melo</string>
    <string name="d24">Cucumis melo, commonly known as muskmelon or cantaloupe, is a species of melon plant known for its sweet and fragrant fruit. The plant is a trailing or climbing vine with large, lobed leaves and tendrils for support. The fruit of Cucumis melo is typically round or oval and features a ribbed or netted rind. The flesh is usually orange, green, or white, depending on the variety, and contains numerous seeds. Muskmelon is known for its sweet and aromatic flavor.</string>
    <string name="dt24">Muskmelons are widely cultivated and enjoyed around the world, but their exact origins are believed to be in the Indian subcontinent, specifically in regions of India and Iran. Today, muskmelons are grown in various countries and are readily available in many parts of the world.</string>
    <string name="m24">While muskmelon is primarily consumed for its delicious taste and high water content, it does offer some potential health benefits:Hydration: Due to its high water content, muskmelon is an excellent choice for staying hydrated, especially in hot weather.Nutrient-Rich: Muskmelons are a good source of essential vitamins and minerals, including vitamin C, vitamin A (in the form of beta-carotene), potassium, and folate.Digestive Health: The dietary fiber in muskmelon can support healthy digestion and help prevent constipation.Weight Management: Muskmelon is low in calories and fat, making it a suitable choice for those looking to manage their weight.</string>
    <string name="b24">Muskmelon offers several potential health benefits, primarily due to its nutrient content:Hydration: Muskmelon\'s high water content helps maintain proper hydration, especially in warm climates.Nutrient Density: It is rich in vitamins and minerals, such as vitamin C, which supports immune health, and vitamin A, which promotes healthy vision.Dietary Fiber: The dietary fiber in muskmelon aids in digestion and can contribute to feelings of fullness, supporting weight management.Antioxidants: Muskmelon contains antioxidants, including beta-carotene, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage.Heart Health: The potassium content in muskmelon may support heart health by helping regulate blood pressure.</string>
    <string name="se24">Muskmelon is generally safe for consumption, but there are a few considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to muskmelon, although such allergies are relatively rare. Allergic reactions can range from mild skin itching to more severe symptoms.Digestive Discomfort: Overconsumption of muskmelon or consuming unripe fruit may lead to digestive discomfort, including diarrhea or stomach cramps.Hygiene: It is essential to wash the exterior of the fruit thoroughly before cutting to prevent contamination.Food Safety: Proper food handling and storage are crucial to prevent bacterial contamination and foodborne illnesses.Overall, muskmelon is a delicious and nutritious fruit that can be enjoyed as part of a healthy diet. However, as with any food, it is essential to consume it in moderation and be mindful of potential allergies or sensitivities.</string>


    <string name="p_25">curculigo orchioides</string>
    <string name="l_25">Kalimusli</string>
    <string name="s_25">Curculigo orchioides</string>
    <string name="f_25">Hypoxidaceae</string>
    <string name="d_25">Curculigo orchioides is a perennial herbaceous plant that is native to India and other parts of Southeast Asia. It is known for its tuberous roots, which have been used in traditional medicine for their potential medicinal properties. The plant typically reaches a height of 30 to 60 centimeters (12 to 24 inches) and has long, narrow leaves that arise from the base. The flowers of Curculigo orchioides are small, yellow, and borne on slender stalks.</string>
    <string name="dt_25">Curculigo orchioides is primarily found in India, where it is native to various regions, including parts of North India and the Western Ghats in the South. It also grows in other parts of Southeast Asia, including countries like Thailand and Malaysia.</string>
    <string name="m_25">The rhizomes (tuberous roots) of Curculigo orchioides have a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda and Siddha medicine. They are believed to possess various potential medicinal properties. Some of the traditional medicinal uses of Curculigo orchioides include:Aphrodisiac: Curculigo orchioides is often used as an aphrodisiac and is believed to enhance sexual vitality and performance in both men and women.Adaptogen: It is considered an adaptogen, which means it may help the body adapt to stress and improve overall resilience.Anti-inflammatory: The plant is used for its anti-inflammatory properties and may help alleviate symptoms of inflammation-related conditions.Antioxidant: Curculigo orchioides contains antioxidants that can help combat free radicals and reduce oxidative stress.Anti-arthritic: It is used to manage symptoms of arthritis and joint pain.</string>
    <string name="b_25">Curculigo orchioides offers several potential health benefits, primarily related to its traditional medicinal uses:Aphrodisiac Properties: It is believed to have aphrodisiac effects, potentially enhancing sexual health and performance.Adaptogenic: Curculigo orchioides may support the body\'s ability to adapt to stress and improve overall well-being.Anti-inflammatory: It may help reduce inflammation and alleviate related symptoms.Antioxidant Effects: The antioxidants in Curculigo orchioides can help protect cells from oxidative damage.</string>
    <string name="se_25">While Curculigo orchioides is generally considered safe when used in traditional medicinal practices, there are a few potential considerations:Dosage: It is essential to use Curculigo orchioides in appropriate dosages as recommended by traditional practitioners or healthcare providers. Excessive consumption may lead to side effects.Pregnancy and Lactation: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider before using Curculigo orchioides supplements or remedies.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to components of the plant and could experience allergic reactions.As with any herbal remedy, it is advisable to seek guidance from a qualified Ayurvedic practitioner, traditional herbalist, or healthcare provider who can provide personalized advice on the proper usage and dosage of Curculigo orchioides based on your specific health needs and conditions.</string>

    <string name="p_26">curcuma longa </string>
    <string name="l_26">Haldar</string>
    <string name="s_26">Curcuma longa</string>
    <string name="f_26">Zingiberaceae (Ginger family)</string>
    <string name="d_26">Curcuma longa is a perennial herbaceous plant native to the Indian subcontinent and Southeast Asia. It is well-known for its bright yellow rhizomes, which are used as a spice and medicinal herb. The plant features large, lance-shaped leaves with a deep green color and grows to a height of approximately 1 meter (3 feet). Turmeric\'s rhizomes are the underground stems, which, when dried and ground, yield the popular spice known for its distinctive color and flavor.</string>
    <string name="dt_26">Turmeric is native to South Asia and has been cultivated for thousands of years in countries like India, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, and Indonesia. It is now cultivated in many tropical regions worldwide, including parts of Africa, the Caribbean, and Central America.</string>
    <string name="m_26">Turmeric has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine. The rhizomes of Curcuma longa contain bioactive compounds, including curcumin, which give turmeric its medicinal properties. Some of the traditional medicinal uses of turmeric include:Anti-inflammatory: Turmeric is known for its potent anti-inflammatory properties and is used to alleviate symptoms of inflammatory conditions such as arthritis.Antioxidant: It acts as an antioxidant, helping to combat free radicals and oxidative stress.Digestive Aid: Turmeric supports digestion and can help relieve digestive discomfort, including gas and bloating.Anti-bacterial: It possesses antibacterial properties and may help combat bacterial infections.Wound Healing: Turmeric has been used topically to promote wound healing and reduce the appearance of scars.</string>
    <string name="b_26">Turmeric offers a wide range of potential health benefits, primarily attributed to its bioactive compound curcumin:Anti-inflammatory: Curcumin\'s anti-inflammatory properties may help reduce inflammation and alleviate symptoms of inflammatory conditions.Antioxidant Effects: Curcumin acts as a potent antioxidant, protecting cells from oxidative damage.Digestive Health: Turmeric can support healthy digestion and relieve digestive discomfort.Joint Health: It may help manage joint pain and stiffness in conditions like osteoarthritis and rheumatoid arthritis.Liver Health: Turmeric may support liver function and help detoxify the body.Anti-cancer: Some research suggests that curcumin may have anti-cancer properties and could inhibit the growth of cancer cells.</string>
    <string name="se_26">Turmeric is generally considered safe when used in culinary amounts. However, there are some considerations:Stomach Upset: In some individuals, high doses of turmeric or curcumin supplements may cause stomach upset, including indigestion and diarrhea.Allergic Reactions: Some people may be sensitive or allergic to turmeric and could experience skin rashes or itching.Interaction with Medications: Turmeric supplements may interact with certain medications, such as blood thinners and diabetes medications. If you are on medication, consult with a healthcare provider before taking turmeric supplements.Pregnancy and Lactation: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use turmeric in moderation as a spice in cooking, but high-dose supplements are not recommended during pregnancy.It is advisable to incorporate turmeric in</string>


    <string name="p27">Datura fastuosa </string>
    <string name="l27">Dhaturo</string>
    <string name="f27">Solanaceae</string>
    <string name="s27">Datura fastuosa</string>
    <string name="d27">Datura fastuosa is a bushy, herbaceous perennial plant that can grow up to 1-1.5 meters in height.It has large, trumpet-shaped flowers that can be white, pale lavender, or even pale yellow in color.The leaves are typically dark green, ovate, and have a wavy or toothed margin.The plant produces spiky seed capsules that are covered in sharp spines.All parts of the plant contain toxic alkaloids, including atropine, scopolamine, and hyoscyamine.</string>
    <string name="dt27">Datura fastuosa is native to North and South America.It has become a widespread invasive plant in many regions, including Europe, Asia, and Africa, where it is often found in disturbed areas, roadsides, and agricultural fields.</string>
    <string name="m27">Datura fastuosa has a long history of use in traditional medicine, particularly by indigenous peoples of the Americas.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Pain relief: The plant\'s alkaloids, particularly atropine and scopolamine, have analgesic properties.Respiratory issues: It has been used to treat asthma and bronchitis due to its bronchodilatory effects.Sedation: In some cases, it has been used as a sedative or to induce sleep.However, its medicinal use is highly dangerous and not recommended due to its extreme toxicity. The therapeutic dose is very close to the lethal dose, making it easy to overdose.</string>
    <string name="b27">Datura fastuosa should not be used for medicinal or recreational purposes due to its extreme toxicity.In modern medicine, its alkaloids are used in very controlled and highly purified forms for specific medical purposes, such as dilating pupils for eye examinations or treating certain types of poisoning.</string>
    <string name="se27">Datura fastuosa is extremely toxic and can have severe and potentially life-threatening side effects, including:HallucinationsDelirium,Rapid heart rate,Dry mouth,Blurred vision,Difficulty urinating,Agitation and aggression,Seizures,Coma,Death in severe cases,Ingesting any part of the plant can be dangerous, and there is a high risk of poisoning.</string>

    <string name="p28">Embelia ribes</string>
    <string name="l28">Vavding</string>
    <string name="s28">Embelia ribes Burm. f.</string>
    <string name="f28">Primulaceae</string>
    <string name="d28">Embelia ribes is a woody, evergreen climbing plant that can reach a height of 3-5 meters.The leaves are elliptical or lance-shaped, and they are typically dark green and glossy.The plant produces small, round berries that are initially green and turn red when ripe.The berries have a pungent, slightly bitter taste.</string>
    <string name="dt28">Embelia ribes is native to the Indian subcontinent, including India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka.It is found in the Himalayan region and in the Western Ghats of India.</string>
    <string name="m28">Embelia ribes has a long history of use in traditional Ayurvedic medicine and other traditional healing systems in India.Some of its traditional medicinal uses include:Antiparasitic: Vidanga is commonly used to treat various parasitic infections, including intestinal worms.Digestive Health: It is used to improve digestion and relieve indigestion.Antimicrobial: Vidanga has demonstrated antimicrobial properties and has been used to treat infections.Carminative: It helps in expelling gas from the digestive system, reducing bloating and flatulence.Anthelmintic: It is particularly valued for its effectiveness against roundworms, tapeworms, and other intestinal parasites.Appetite Stimulant: Vidanga is also used as an appetite stimulant.</string>
    <string name="se28">When used in appropriate doses and under the guidance of a qualified healthcare practitioner, Embelia ribes is generally considered safe.However, excessive or prolonged use can lead to side effects, including nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, and abdominal discomfort.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use it cautiously, and it should be avoided by individuals with allergies or hypersensitivity to the plant.</string>
    <string name="b28">The primary benefit of Embelia ribes lies in its anthelmintic and antiparasitic properties. It is considered an effective natural remedy for various types of parasitic infections, especially in traditional medicine systems like Ayurveda.Its use as a digestive aid can help alleviate gastrointestinal discomfort and promote overall digestive health.It has been studied for its potential antioxidant and antimicrobial properties, which may have broader health benefits.</string>


    <string name="p29">Feroniu limonia</string>
    <string name="l29">Kathi</string>
    <string name="s29">Feronia limonia (L.) Swingle</string>
    <string name="f29">Rutaceae</string>
    <string name="d29">Feronia limonia is a slow-growing, deciduous tree that can reach heights of up to 9 meters.The tree is known for its dense, thorny branches and pinnate leaves.The fruit, known as wood apple or elephant apple, is typically round and has a hard, woody shell.The pulp inside is aromatic and sweet-sour in taste and is surrounded by a mucilaginous layer.</string>
    <string name="dt29">Feronia limonia is native to the Indian subcontinent, particularly India and Sri Lanka.It is also found in other parts of Southeast Asia, including Bangladesh, Myanmar, and Thailand.</string>
    <string name="m29">Feronia limonia has been used in traditional medicine for various purposes. Some of its traditional medicinal uses include:Digestive Health: The fruit is known for its digestive properties and is often consumed to relieve indigestion and constipation.Antioxidant Properties: It contains antioxidants like vitamin C and flavonoids, which can help combat oxidative stress in the body.Respiratory Ailments: It is sometimes used to alleviate symptoms of respiratory conditions like asthma and bronchitis.Anti-inflammatory: The fruit pulp is applied topically to reduce inflammation and soothe skin conditions.Immune Boosting: Due to its vitamin C content, it may help boost the immune system.</string>
    <string name="b29">Wood apple is a nutritious fruit rich in vitamins (especially vitamin C), minerals, and dietary fiber.It is known for its ability to improve digestion and relieve gastrointestinal issues, making it a popular remedy for constipation and diarrhea.The antioxidants in wood apple may help protect cells from damage caused by free radicals.Some traditional systems of medicine utilize different parts of the tree, including the bark and leaves, for various therapeutic purposes.</string>
    <string name="se29">When consumed in moderation, wood apple is generally safe for most people.However, consuming excessive amounts of the fruit can lead to digestive discomfort, as it is quite fibrous.Some people may be allergic to certain components of the fruit, leading to allergic reactions.</string>


    <string name="p30"> Ficus amplissima Smith</string>
    <string name="l30">"Pipal "</string>
    <string name="s30"> Ficus amplissima Smith</string>
    <string name="f30">Moraceae</string>
    <string name="d30">Ficus amplissima is a large, evergreen tree that can reach heights of up to 30 meters or more.The leaves are simple, alternate, and elliptical in shape with a glossy, dark green color. They are around 10-20 cm long and have prominent veins.The tree produces small, axillary, spherical fig fruits that start green and mature to a purplish-black color.</string>
    <string name="dt30">Ficus amplissima is native to various regions of Asia, including India, Sri Lanka, Myanmar, and Thailand.It is often found in tropical and subtropical regions and is known to grow in a variety of habitats, including forests and along riverbanks.</string>
    <string name="m30">Various parts of the Ficus amplissima plant have been used in traditional medicine for a range of purposes:The latex from the tree has been used as a traditional remedy for treating skin diseases and wounds.The leaves and bark have been employed to treat conditions such as diarrhea, dysentery, and stomach disorders.The latex is sometimes applied topically to treat fungal infections and skin issues.Please note that while Ficus amplissima has been used in traditional medicine, its efficacy and safety for these purposes have not been extensively studied, and it\'s essential to consult with a healthcare professional before using it for medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="b30">Ficus amplissima offers several potential benefits:The fruit of this tree is edible and is consumed by both humans and wildlife.It provides shade and shelter to various animals and birds.The tree is sometimes used in landscaping and afforestation due to its large and attractive canopy.</string>
    <string name="se30">There aren\'t many documented side effects associated with the use of Ficus amplissima for traditional medicinal purposes, but it\'s crucial to exercise caution and seek professional guidance when using plants for therapeutic applications. Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to certain components of the plant.Additionally, the latex from Ficus species can be irritating to the skin and mucous membranes for some people.</string>


    <string name="p31">Foeniculum vulgare</string>
    <string name="l31">variyali</string>
    <string name="s31">Foeniculum vulgare Mill.</string>
    <string name="f31">Apiaceae (formerly known as Umbelliferae)</string>
    <string name="d31">Foeniculum vulgare, or Fennel, is a herbaceous perennial plant that typically grows to a height of 1-2 meters.It has finely divided, feathery leaves that are green and aromatic.The plant produces clusters of small, yellow flowers that resemble umbrellas, hence its classification in the Apiaceae family.Fennel seeds are one of the most commonly used parts of the plant, known for their aromatic flavor and culinary uses.</string>
    <string name="dt31">Fennel is native to the Mediterranean region but has become widely naturalized in many parts of the world.It is commonly found in Europe, Asia, North America, and other temperate regions.In some areas, it also grows wild and can be invasive.</string>
    <string name="m31">ennel has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda and Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM).Some of its traditional medicinal uses include:Digestive Aid: Fennel seeds are often consumed after meals to aid digestion and relieve bloating, gas, and indigestion.Respiratory Health: Fennel is used to alleviate respiratory issues, such as coughs and bronchitis, due to its expectorant properties.Menstrual Disorders: It is believed to help regulate menstruation and relieve symptoms of PMS (premenstrual syndrome).Lactation Support: Fennel is thought to increase milk production in breastfeeding women.Appetite Suppressant: Chewing fennel seeds is sometimes used as a natural appetite suppressant.</string>
    <string name="b31">Fennel seeds are rich in essential oils, particularly anethole, which gives them their characteristic flavor and aroma.The seeds are low in calories but provide dietary fiber, vitamins (such as vitamin C), and minerals (like potassium).Due to their aromatic nature and mild flavor, fennel seeds are commonly used as a culinary spice and as a flavoring agent in a variety of dishes, including soups, salads, and baked goods.Fennel tea is a popular herbal remedy for digestive complaints and is used to promote overall digestive health.</string>
    <string name="se31">Fennel is generally considered safe for most people when consumed in moderation as a food or herbal remedy.Some individuals may be allergic to fennel, resulting in skin reactions or respiratory symptoms.In rare cases, excessive consumption of fennel seeds or fennel oil may lead to side effects such as nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea.Pregnant women should avoid consuming large amounts of fennel due to concerns about potential uterine stimulant effects.</string>


    <string name="p32">Gaultheria fragrantissima</string>
    <string name="l32">Himantharet </string>
    <string name="s32">Gaultheria fragrantissima Wall.</string>
    <string name="f32">Ericaceae</string>
    <string name="d32">Gaultheria fragrantissima is a small evergreen shrub that typically grows to a height of 15-30 centimeters.The leaves are elliptical, dark green, and glossy. When crushed or bruised, the leaves release a strong, pleasant aroma, giving the plant its name "fragrantissima."The plant produces small, white to pinkish, bell-shaped flowers that hang downward.The fruits of Gaultheria fragrantissima are small, red, and berry-like.</string>
    <string name="dt32">Gaultheria fragrantissima is native to the Himalayan region, including countries like India, Nepal, Bhutan, and Tibet.It is typically found in cool, temperate, and subalpine regions, often in forests or mountainous areas.</string>
    <string name="m32">Gaultheria fragrantissima has been used traditionally in herbal medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Tibetan medicine.The plant\'s essential oil is highly valued for its medicinal properties.Some of its traditional medicinal uses include:Analgesic: Wintergreen oil is known for its pain-relieving properties and is used topically to alleviate muscle aches, joint pain, and headaches.Anti-inflammatory: The oil is used to reduce inflammation in conditions like arthritis.Antiseptic: It has been applied to wounds to prevent infection.Aromatherapy: The oil is used in aromatherapy for its soothing and uplifting scent, which can help relieve stress and anxiety.</string>
    <string name="b32">The primary benefit of Gaultheria fragrantissima lies in its essential oil, which contains methyl salicylate, a compound with pain-relieving and anti-inflammatory properties.Wintergreen oil is commonly used in topical applications, such as massage oils and liniments, for pain relief.Its pleasant aroma makes it a popular choice in aromatherapy for promoting relaxation and reducing stress.Some people find it beneficial for relieving the symptoms of common colds and respiratory congestion when used in steam inhalation.</string>
    <string name="se32">Wintergreen oil should be used with caution and diluted when applied topically, as it contains a high concentration of methyl salicylate, which can be toxic if absorbed in large amounts through the skin.Ingesting wintergreen oil or its components can be toxic and even fatal, especially in children, due to its salicylate content, which is related to aspirin.Allergic reactions to wintergreen oil are rare but possible, so it\'s advisable to perform a patch test before using it topically.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should avoid using wintergreen oil due to potential risks.</string>

    <string name="p33">Gerwia tenax</string>
    <string name="l33">Gangeti </string>
    <string name="s33">Grewia tenax</string>
    <string name="f33">Malvaceae</string>
    <string name="d33">Grewia tenax is a small deciduous shrub or tree that can grow up to 4-6 meters in height. The plant has slender branches with leaves that are serrated and elliptical in shape. The leaves are green and have a rough texture. The flowers of Grewia tenax are small and inconspicuous, typically greenish-white or pale yellow. The fruit is the most prominent part of the plant and is small, round, and berry-like, measuring about 1-1.5 cm in diameter. The fruits are initially green and turn dark purple to black when ripe.</string>
    <string name="dt33">Grewia tenax is native to South Asia and is found in various regions, including India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Nepal, Sri Lanka, and parts of Southeast Asia. It is well adapted to arid and semi-arid regions and can be found in both wild and cultivated forms.</string>
    <string name="m33">Grewia tenax has a long history of traditional medicinal use in various cultures. Different parts of the plant, including the leaves, bark, and fruit, are used for various therapeutic purposes.The leaves and bark are used to treat ailments such as diarrhea, dysentery, and stomach disorders. They are often boiled to make a decoction and consumed.The fruit is rich in vitamin C and is used as a remedy for scurvy and to boost the immune system.The roots are believed to have astringent properties and are used to treat dental issues, including gum problems and toothaches.</string>
    <string name="b33">Rich in Antioxidants: The fruit of Grewia tenax is rich in antioxidants, particularly vitamin C, which can help combat oxidative stress and boost the immune system.Nutrient-Rich: The fruit contains essential nutrients such as vitamins and minerals, making it a valuable addition to the diet in regions where it grows.Diarrhea Treatment: The plant\'s leaves and bark have astringent properties and are used to treat diarrhea and related gastrointestinal issues.</string>
    <string name="se33">Grewia tenax is generally considered safe when consumed in moderation as food or for medicinal purposes. However, excessive consumption of the fruit may cause digestive discomfort in some individuals.It\'s always advisable to consult with a healthcare professional before using any plant or plant-derived remedies for medicinal purposes, especially if you have pre-existing medical conditions or are taking medications.</string>

    <string name="p34">Gloriosa superba</string>
    <string name="l34">Vachhaf!ag </string>
    <string name="s34">Gloriosa superba</string>
    <string name="f34">Colchicaceae (formerly included in the Liliaceae family)</string>
    <string name="d34">loriosa superba is a striking and climbing perennial plant known for its stunning, colorful flowers.It features long, slender vines that can grow up to 2 meters or more in length.The leaves are lance-shaped, pointed, and typically arranged alternately along the vines.The flowers are the most distinctive feature, with flame-like petals that can be red, yellow, orange, or a combination of these colors. They often have a wavy or curly appearance.Gloriosa superba produces tuberous roots.</string>
    <string name="dt34">This plant is native to tropical and subtropical regions of Africa and Asia.It can be found in countries such as India, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Myanmar, and several African nations.In some regions, it is cultivated as an ornamental plant.</string>
    <string name="m34">Gloriosa superba contains several alkaloids, including colchicine and gloriosine, which have been used in traditional medicine for various purposes.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Treatment of gout: Colchicine from the plant has been used to relieve the symptoms of gout, a painful joint condition.Treatment of rheumatism and arthritis: Colchicine may help reduce inflammation and pain in these conditions.Antipyretic (fever-reducing) properties: Gloriosa superba has been used to reduce fever.However, the plant is highly toxic, and its use for medicinal purposes is risky and not recommended without proper medical guidance.</string>
    <string name="b34">Gloriosa superba is primarily grown as an ornamental plant due to its stunning and unique flowers.Its vibrant and colorful blooms make it a popular choice for gardens and floral arrangements.In some traditional cultures, it is also associated with symbolism and religious or cultural rituals.</string>
    <string name="se34">Gloriosa superba is one of the most toxic plants in the world. All parts of the plant, especially the tubers, contain toxic alkaloids, including colchicine.Ingesting any part of the plant can lead to severe poisoning, which may result in symptoms such as vomiting, diarrhea, organ failure, convulsions, and death.Handling the plant without protective measures can also lead to skin irritation and allergic reactions.Due to its extreme toxicity, Gloriosa superba should be handled with extreme caution, and its use for medicinal purposes is highly discouraged.</string>

    <string name="p35">Gmelina arborea </string>
    <string name="l35">Shevan  </string>
    <string name="s35">Gmelina arborea Roxb.</string>
    <string name="f35">Lamiaceae (formerly placed in the Verbenaceae family)</string>
    <string name="d35">Gmelina arborea is a fast-growing, deciduous tree that can reach heights of up to 30 meters.The leaves are simple, opposite, and broadly ovate with a pointed tip.The bark is smooth, gray, and slightly flaky.The flowers are yellowish-orange and trumpet-shaped, and they are arranged in axillary or terminal clusters.The fruit is a small, brown capsule containing winged seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt35">Gmelina arborea is native to South and Southeast Asia, including countries such as India, Myanmar, Thailand, and Indonesia.It is widely cultivated and naturalized in various tropical and subtropical regions around the world.</string>
    <string name="m35">Gmelina arborea has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Antipyretic: The bark and leaves are used to reduce fever.Anti-inflammatory: Preparations from the plant have been used to alleviate inflammation.Antioxidant: The leaves are believed to possess antioxidant properties.Wound healing: Pastes made from various parts of the plant have been applied to wounds to promote healing.Analgesic: In some regions, the bark has been used for pain relief.It is important to note that while Gmelina arborea has traditional medicinal uses, scientific evidence supporting these uses is limited, and caution should be exercis</string>
    <string name="b35">Timber: Gmelina arborea is primarily valued for its wood, which is often referred to as "Gmelina wood" or "Beechwood." The wood is lightweight, easy to work with, and used for a variety of purposes, including furniture, construction, and plywood.Agroforestry: The tree is also used in agroforestry systems to provide shade and support the growth of other crops.Fuelwood: In some regions, it is used as a source of fuelwood and charcoal</string>
    <string name="se35">While Gmelina arborea is not considered highly toxic, the plant\'s medicinal use should be approached with caution and preferably under the guidance of a qualified healthcare practitioner or herbalist.Some people may experience allergic reactions when in contact with the plant or its extracts.Overuse or misuse of any herbal remedy can lead to adverse effects, and it\'s essential to use Gmelina arborea for medicinal purposes in moderation and with appropriate preparations.</string>

    <string name="p36">Helianthus annuus </string>
    <string name="l36">Suryamukhi </string>
    <string name="s36">Helianthus annuus</string>
    <string name="f36">Asteraceae (Compositae)</string>
    <string name="d36">Helianthus annuus, or the Sunflower, is an annual flowering plant known for its large and distinctive flower head.The plant typically grows to heights ranging from 1.5 meters to 3 meters or more.Sunflower leaves are generally heart-shaped or ovate with serrated edges.The flower head is composed of numerous bright yellow ray florets surrounding a central disc of darker, tubular florets.The plant produces large, flat, and oval-shaped seeds that are commonly consumed and used in various ways.</string>
    <string name="dt36">Sunflowers are native to North and Central America.They are now cultivated and grown as a crop in many parts of the world, including North America, Europe, Asia, and Africa.They thrive in areas with plenty of sunlight and well-drained soil.</string>
    <string name="m36">While Sunflowers are primarily cultivated for their seeds and oil, various parts of the plant have been used in traditional medicine in some cultures.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Antioxidant Properties: Sunflower seeds contain vitamin E, which has antioxidant properties and may help protect cells from oxidative damage.Skin Health: Sunflower oil is used in some skincare products for its moisturizing and soothing properties.Anti-Inflammatory: In traditional medicine, preparations made from Sunflower leaves have been used for their potential anti-inflammatory effects.Respiratory Health: In certain traditional systems, Sunflower extracts have been used to alleviate respiratory issues.Diuretic: Some cultures have used Sunflower preparations as diuretics to promote urination.It\'s important to note that while Sunflowers have some potential medicinal uses, scientific research on their medicinal properties is ongoing, and they are not a primary source of medicine in modern healthcare systems.</string>
    <string name="b36">Sunflowers are primarily grown for their seeds and oil. Sunflower seeds are rich in nutrients, including vitamins (especially vitamin E), minerals, and healthy fats.Sunflower oil is widely used for cooking, salad dressings, and in various food products.The seeds are a popular snack and can be eaten roasted or raw.Sunflowers are also grown for their ornamental value in gardens and landscapes due to their bright and cheerful flowers.</string>
    <string name="se36">Sunflower seeds and oil are generally considered safe for most people when consumed in moderation as part of a balanced diet.Some individuals may be allergic to Sunflower seeds or oil, which can lead to allergic reactions, such as skin rash, itching, or digestive discomfort.Overconsumption of Sunflower seeds can lead to excessive calorie intake, which may contribute to weight gain if not managed as part of a healthy diet.When using Sunflower oil for cooking, it\'s essential to avoid overheating, as it can lead to the formation of harmful compounds.</string>

    <string name="p37">Hemidesmus indicus  </string>
    <string name="l37">Anantvel </string>
    <string name="s37">Hemidesmus indicus</string>
    <string name="f37">Apocynaceae</string>
    <string name="d37">Hemidesmus indicus is a perennial, twining, and woody shrub that can grow up to 1-1.5 meters in height.The leaves are simple, opposite, and lance-shaped, typically around 5-8 cm long.The plant produces small, tubular, pale greenish-white flowers arranged in clusters.The root system is extensive, with slender, aromatic roots that are used for medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="dt37">Hemidesmus indicus is native to the Indian subcontinent, including India, Sri Lanka, and parts of Southeast Asia.It is also cultivated in other tropical and subtropical regions around the world.</string>
    <string name="m37">Indian Sarsaparilla, or Hemidesmus indicus, has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, including Ayurveda and Siddha.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Blood Purifier: Indian Sarsaparilla is often used to purify the blood and remove toxins from the body.Anti-Inflammatory: It is used to alleviate inflammation and pain in conditions like arthritis.Digestive Health: It may help improve digestion and relieve gastrointestinal issues.Respiratory Health: It is used to soothe coughs and respiratory conditions.Skin Health: Indian Sarsaparilla is believed to promote healthy skin and treat skin disorders.Detoxification: It is used in detoxification and purification therapies.Fever Reduction: It has been used to reduce fever.It is essential to note that while Indian Sarsaparilla has traditional uses, scientific research on its medicinal properties is ongoing, and its effectiveness for some of these purposes may vary.</string>
    <string name="b37">Indian Sarsaparilla is known for its potential health benefits, primarily attributed to its bioactive compounds.It contains phytochemicals such as saponins, flavonoids, and alkaloids, which are believed to contribute to its medicinal properties.Some people use Indian Sarsaparilla as a natural remedy for various health issues, including skin problems, joint pain, and digestive discomfort.It is also valued for its pleasant aroma and is used in perfumes and traditional incense.</string>
    <string name="se37">When used in appropriate doses and under the guidance of a qualified healthcare practitioner, Indian Sarsaparilla is generally considered safe for most people.Excessive or prolonged use may lead to potential side effects such as stomach upset, diarrhea, or skin reactions in some individuals.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use it with caution, and it is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using it, especially if you have specific medical conditions or concerns.</string>

    <string name="p38">Holarrhena pube-scens </string>
    <string name="l38">Indrajav </string>
    <string name="s38">Holarrhena pubescens Wall.</string>
    <string name="f38">Apocynaceae</string>
    <string name="d38">Holarrhena pubescens is a small to medium-sized deciduous tree that typically grows to a height of 3-8 meters.The leaves are opposite, elliptical, and have a characteristic pubescent (hairy) appearance on the undersides.The flowers are typically small, white, and fragrant, and they are arranged in cymes.The fruit is a pair of slender, cylindrical follicles that contain numerous seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt38">Holarrhena pubescens is native to the Indian subcontinent, including India, Sri Lanka, and Nepal.It is also found in parts of Southeast Asia and tropical regions of Africa.The plant thrives in a variety of habitats, including forests, grasslands, and wastelands.</string>
    <string name="m38">Holarrhena pubescens has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and Unani medicine.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Anti-Diarrheal: The bark and seeds are used to treat diarrhea and dysentery due to their astringent properties.Anti-Malarial: Certain compounds in the plant have been investigated for their potential use against malaria.Antispasmodic: It is used to relieve spasms and cramps.Digestive Health: Holarrhena pubescens is believed to improve digestion.Worm Infestations: It has been used to expel intestinal worms.Fever Reduction: In some traditional systems, it is used to reduce fever.Research has indicated that certain alkaloids, including conessine, found in the plant may contribute to its medicinal properties.</string>
    <string name="b38">The primary benefit of Holarrhena pubescens lies in its traditional medicinal uses, particularly for the treatment of gastrointestinal disorders.It is valued for its potential as an anti-diarrheal and anti-dysentery remedy.The plant\'s alkaloids have been the subject of scientific investigation for their pharmacological properties, including their impact on the central nervous system and potential anti-malarial activity.</string>
    <string name="se38">When used in appropriate doses and under the guidance of a qualified healthcare practitioner, Holarrhena pubescens is generally considered safe for most people.However, excessive use or misuse may lead to potential side effects, including digestive discomfort and toxicity.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use it with caution, and it is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using it, especially if you have specific medical conditions or concerns.Due to its potential toxicity, the plant should be used judiciously and preferably under the guidance of a qualified herbalist or healthcare practitioner.</string>

    <string name="p39">Hydrolea zeylanica Vahl</string>
    <string name="l39">Kerite </string>
    <string name="s39">Hydrolea zeylanica Vahl</string>
    <string name="f39">Boraginaceae</string>
    <string name="d39">Hydrolea zeylanica is a perennial herb or subshrub that grows in wet and marshy areas.It typically reaches a height of about 30-60 cm.The leaves are lanceolate or elliptical, with serrated edges and a pointed tip.The flowers are small, funnel-shaped, and can be blue, purple, or white, depending on the variety.The plant\'s roots are often submerged in water or moist soil.</string>
    <string name="dt39">Hydrolea zeylanica is native to various parts of Asia, including India, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, and Thailand.It is often found in swampy areas, marshes, and along the banks of water bodies.</string>
    <string name="m39">This plant has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Tamil medicine.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Anti-Inflammatory: Hydrolea zeylanica is used to reduce inflammation and swelling.Diuretic: It is used as a diuretic to increase urine flow.Anti-Diabetic: Some traditional practitioners use it for managing diabetes.Anti-Rheumatic: It is used to alleviate symptoms of rheumatic conditions.Skin Disorders: It may be applied topically for skin issues.Fever Reduction: In some traditional systems, it is used to reduce fever.Gastrointestinal Health: It is used for digestive complaints.While it has traditional uses, scientific research on its medicinal properties is limited, and more studies are needed to validate its effectiveness for these purposes.</string>
    <string name="b39">The primary benefit of Hydrolea zeylanica lies in its traditional medicinal uses, especially for conditions related to inflammation, diuresis, and digestive health.It is valued in traditional systems for its potential to promote overall wellness.</string>
    <string name="se39">When used in appropriate doses and under the guidance of a qualified healthcare practitioner, Hydrolea zeylanica is generally considered safe for most people.However, excessive use or misuse may lead to potential side effects, including digestive discomfort.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use it with caution, and it is advisable to consult a healthcare professional before using it, especially if you have specific medical conditions or concerns.As with any herbal remedy, it is important to use it judiciously and preferably under the guidance of a qualified herbalist or healthcare practitioner to ensure safe and effective use</string>

    <!--    <string name="p40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="l40">/string>-->
    <!--    <string name="s40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="f40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="d40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="dt40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="m40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="b40"></string>-->
    <!--    <string name="se40"></string>-->

    <string name="p41">Ipomoea turbinata</string>
    <string name="l41">Vajval</string>
    <string name="s41">Ipomoea turbinata</string>
    <string name="f41">Convolvulaceae</string>
    <string name="d41">Ipomoea turbinata is a creeping or trailing herbaceous plant that is typically found along coastal areas, especially on sandy beaches and dunes. The plant has the following characteristics:Leaves: The leaves are thick, fleshy, and usually heart-shaped. They are typically about 5-10 cm long and can be slightly lobed.Flowers: The flowers are trumpet-shaped and come in a range of colors, including pink, purple, or white. They are usually around 5 cm in diameter and bloom during the day.Stems: The stems are prostrate and often form dense mats, which help stabilize sand dunes and prevent erosion.</string>
    <string name="dt41">Ipomoea turbinata is native to coastal regions of Asia, particularly in countries like India, Thailand, Malaysia, Indonesia, and the Philippines. It\'s well-adapted to sandy coastal habitats and thrives in tropical and subtropical climates.</string>
    <string name="m41">The plant has been used in traditional medicine in various ways:Asthma and Cough: In some traditional systems, the leaves are used to treat respiratory issues, including asthma and coughs.Anti-Inflammatory: The plant\'s extracts have been investigated for their potential anti-inflammatory properties.Wound Healing: In some regions, a poultice made from crushed leaves is applied to wounds to promote healing.Antioxidant: Some research suggests that Beach Morning Glory contains antioxidants, which can have health benefits.</string>
    <string name="b41">Soil Stabilization: Ipomoea turbinata plays a crucial role in stabilizing coastal dunes. Its extensive root system helps bind sand, preventing it from eroding, especially during storms and high tides.Ornamental Plant: The attractive flowers of Beach Morning Glory make it a popular choice for ornamental planting in gardens and along coastlines.Wildlife Habitat: The plant provides habitat and food for various coastal wildlife, including insects and birds.</string>
    <string name="se41">While Ipomoea turbinata is generally considered safe, some individuals may be allergic to the plant. Allergic reactions could manifest as skin rashes or respiratory symptoms if the plant is handled or ingested.</string>


    <string name="p42">Lepidium satiuum </string>
    <string name="l42">Aselio</string>
    <string name="s42">Lepidium satiuum </string>
    <string name="f42">Brassicaceae (Cruciferae)</string>
    <string name="d42">Lepidium sativum, commonly known as Garden Cress, is an annual herbaceous plant.It typically grows to a height of 20-50 cm.The leaves are compound, pinnate, and finely divided, resembling delicate fern fronds.The small flowers are white or pale pink and form in clusters.The plant produces small, round or oval-shaped seeds that are used for culinary and medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="dt42">Garden Cress is native to parts of North Africa and Western Asia.It is cultivated and grown in many regions around the world, including Europe, Asia, and North America.It can thrive in a variety of climates and is often grown as a cool-season crop.</string>
    <string name="m42">Garden Cress has a history of use in traditional medicine and is valued for its potential health benefits.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Respiratory Health: It is used to relieve coughs and respiratory congestion.Digestive Health: Garden Cress is believed to aid digestion and alleviate gastrointestinal discomfort.Lactation Support: In some cultures, it is used to promote lactation in nursing mothers.Anti-Inflammatory: It is used for its potential anti-inflammatory properties.Vitamin and Mineral Source: Garden Cress is rich in vitamins (particularly vitamin C) and minerals.Garden Cress seeds, in particular, are consumed for their purported health benefits.</string>
    <string name="b42">Garden Cress is valued for its nutritional content, which includes vitamins (such as vitamin C, vitamin A, and vitamin K), minerals (such as calcium, iron, and magnesium), and antioxidants.The seeds are often used in culinary dishes, especially in salads, sandwiches, and as a garnish.Due to its nutritional profile, Garden Cress is considered a healthy addition to a balanced diet.</string>
    <string name="se42">When consumed in moderate amounts as part of a normal diet, Garden Cress is generally considered safe for most people.However, excessive consumption may lead to potential side effects, such as digestive discomfort.Allergic reactions to Garden Cress are rare but possible, so individuals with known allergies to plants in the Brassicaceae family (like mustard or cabbage) should exercise caution.As with any dietary addition or supplement, it is important to use Garden Cress in moderation.</string>


    <string name="p43">Lycium barbarum</string>
    <string name="l43">Kachoro</string>
    <string name="s43">Lycium barbarum</string>
    <string name="f43">Solanaceae</string>
    <string name="d43">Lycium barbarum is a deciduous woody shrub belonging to the nightshade family (Solanaceae).It typically grows to a height of 1-3 meters.The leaves are lance-shaped and arranged alternately along the branches.The flowers are small and bell-shaped, usually purple or lavender.The plant produces small, red, oblong-shaped berries that are used both for culinary and medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="dt43">Lycium barbarum is native to regions of China, including the Himalayas, as well as parts of Mongolia and Tibet.It is also cultivated in other regions, including the Mediterranean, North America, and various parts of Asia.Goji berries are now grown and enjoyed worldwide.</string>
    <string name="m43">Goji berries have been used for their potential health benefits in traditional Chinese medicine for centuries.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Immune System Support: They are believed to boost the immune system.Antioxidant Properties: Goji berries are rich in antioxidants, which may help protect cells from oxidative damage.Eye Health: Traditionally, they are used to support eye health.Liver Health: In traditional medicine, they may be used to support liver function.Anti-Aging: They are sometimes associated with anti-aging properties.Goji berries are consumed fresh, dried, or in various preparations such as teas, tinctures, and supplements.</string>
    <string name="b43">Goji berries are rich in nutrients, including vitamins (such as vitamin C, vitamin A, and various B vitamins), minerals (such as iron, zinc, and selenium), and essential amino acids.They are a good source of dietary fiber.Goji berries are known for their antioxidant properties, which can help combat oxidative stress and inflammation in the body.Some studies suggest that Goji berries may support eye health, improve immune function, and have anti-aging effects, although further research is needed to confirm these benefits.</string>
    <string name="se43">Goji berries are generally considered safe when consumed in moderation as part of a balanced diet.Some individuals may experience allergic reactions or gastrointestinal discomfort, particularly if consumed in excessive amounts.If you are taking medications or have underlying health conditions, it\'s advisable to consult with a healthcare professional before adding significant quantities of Goji berries to your diet or taking Goji berry supplements.Pregnant or breastfeeding women should also exercise caution and consult a healthcare provider.</string>


    <string name="p44">Moringa oleifera Lam</string>
    <string name="l44">Sargavo</string>
    <string name="s44">Moringa oleifera Lam</string>
    <string name="f44">Moringaceae</string>
    <string name="d44">Moringa oleifera is a fast-growing, deciduous tree native to the Indian subcontinent and parts of Asia and Africa.It typically reaches a height of 8-12 meters but can grow taller under favorable conditions.The leaves are compound, feathery, and pinnately divided, resembling fern fronds.The tree produces fragrant, creamy-white flowers with five petals.The fruit is a long, slender, green pod, often referred to as a "drumstick," containing seeds.The seeds are enclosed in a papery wing and are sometimes called "drumstick seeds."</string>
    <string name="dt44">Moringa oleifera is native to northern India, but it is now widely cultivated and naturalized in tropical and subtropical regions around the world.It thrives in a variety of climates and soil types, making it adaptable to different environments</string>
    <string name="m44">Moringa oleifera has a rich history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional African medicine.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Nutrient-Rich: Moringa leaves are exceptionally rich in vitamins, minerals, and essential amino acids.Anti-Inflammatory: The leaves and other parts of the plant are used for their potential anti-inflammatory properties.Antioxidant: Moringa is known for its antioxidant content, which can help combat oxidative stress.Nutritional Supplementation: It is used to address nutritional deficiencies, especially in communities with limited access to diverse foods.Digestive Health: Moringa is believed to support digestion and relieve digestive discomfort.Moringa leaves, seeds, and oil are often incorporated into traditional remedies.</string>
    <string name="b44">Moringa is considered a superfood due to its exceptional nutritional content. It is rich in vitamins (such as vitamin A, vitamin C, and B vitamins), minerals (including calcium, iron, and potassium), and protein.It is a source of antioxidants, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage.Moringa leaves and pods are consumed as a vegetable in many cuisines.Moringa oil is used for various purposes, including in cosmetics and as a cooking oil.The seeds contain an oil that is used for their potential health benefits.</string>
    <string name="se44">Moringa is generally safe when consumed as part of a balanced diet.However, some individuals may experience digestive discomfort (such as gas or diarrhea) when consuming large quantities of Moringa.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should consume Moringa in moderation and consult with a healthcare provider.Excessive use of Moringa supplements or extracts may lead to potential side effects, so it\'s important to follow recommended dosages.</string>


    <string name="p45">Musa paradisiaca</string>
    <string name="l45">Kel</string>
    <string name="s45">Musa paradisiaca</string>
    <string name="f45">Musaceae</string>
    <string name="d45">Musa paradisiaca is a large herbaceous plant characterized by its pseudostem (false stem), large leaves, and fruit clusters.The pseudostem is composed of tightly packed leaf bases, and it supports the large leaves.The leaves are long, broad, and have a characteristic pinnate venation.The flowers of Musa paradisiaca are distinctive and appear in large, pendulous clusters called "hands."The fruit of the banana plant is a long, curved or straight berry, and it is botanically classified as a "berry" rather than a true fruit.</string>
    <string name="dt45">Musa paradisiaca is believed to have originated in Southeast Asia, but it is now cultivated in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.It is a staple food in many countries with warm climates and is grown extensively in Africa, Asia, Latin America, and the Caribbean.Bananas and plantains thrive in areas with abundant rainfall and warm temperatures.</string>
    <string name="m45">While bananas and plantains are primarily consumed as a source of nutrition, they also have some traditional medicinal uses:Digestive Health: Bananas and plantains are known for their mild, soothing effect on the digestive system and are often recommended for individuals with upset stomachs or diarrhea.Rich Source of Nutrients: They are a good source of essential vitamins and minerals, including potassium, vitamin C, vitamin B6, and dietary fiber, which can contribute to overall health.Energy Boost: Bananas are popular among athletes for their quick energy release due to their carbohydrate content.These uses are not considered a substitute for medical treat</string>
    <string name="b45">Bananas and plantains are nutritious and provide a variety of health benefits:Energy: They are a good source of carbohydrates, which provide a quick source of energy.Potassium: Bananas are rich in potassium, which is important for heart health and maintaining proper blood pressure.Vitamins and Minerals: They contain essential vitamins and minerals, including vitamin C, vitamin B6, and folate.Digestive Health: The dietary fiber in bananas and plantains supports healthy digestion.Antioxidants: They contain antioxidants, such as dopamine and catechins, which can help protect cells from damage.</string>
    <string name="se45">Bananas and plantains are generally safe for most people when consumed as part of a balanced diet.Some individuals with allergies may experience oral allergy syndrome (itching or swelling of the mouth) when consuming raw bananas or plantains.Overconsumption of bananas or plantains can lead to excessive calorie intake, which may contribute to weight gain if not managed within a balanced diet.People with certain medical conditions, such as kidney disease, may need to monitor their potassium intake and consult with a healthcare provider.</string>


    <string name="p46">Nicotiana tabacum</string>
    <string name="l46">Tambaku</string>
    <string name="s46">Nicotiana tabacum</string>
    <string name="f46">Solanaceae</string>
    <string name="d46">Nicotiana tabacum is an annual or short-lived perennial plant that belongs to the nightshade family (Solanaceae).It is characterized by broad, sticky leaves that contain nicotine, an alkaloid responsible for its addictive properties.The plant typically grows to a height of 1-2 meters, although specific varieties may vary.The flowers of tobacco are typically pink or white and arranged in clusters.</string>
    <string name="dt46">Nicotiana tabacum is native to the Americas, with a likely origin in the region now encompassing parts of Peru and Ecuador.After European exploration and colonization of the Americas, tobacco was introduced to Europe, where it became a major crop.Today, tobacco is cultivated worldwide in regions with suitable climates, including the United States, China, India, and various countries in Africa and South America.</string>
    <string name="m46">Historically, tobacco has been used in various ways for its medicinal properties by indigenous peoples of the Americas.Some traditional medicinal uses have included:Pain Relief: Tobacco leaves were sometimes used topically or in poultices to relieve pain or discomfort.Sedative: In some cultures, tobacco was used as a sedative or relaxant.Ceremonial and Spiritual Use: Tobacco was an important part of ceremonial and spiritual practices for many indigenous groups.However, it is essential to note that the medicinal use of tobacco is highly discouraged due to its well-documented health risks and potential for addiction.</string>
    <string name="b46">While tobacco is primarily known for its recreational use as a source of nicotine, it has not been associated with significant health benefits. Instead, it is widely recognized as a major public health concern due to its association with a range of serious health issues.</string>
    <string name="se46">Tobacco use, particularly smoking, is linked to numerous adverse health effects, including but not limited to:Addiction: Nicotine is highly addictive, and tobacco use can lead to physical and psychological dependence.Cancer: Smoking tobacco is a leading cause of lung cancer and is associated with various other cancers, including mouth, throat, and bladder cancer.Respiratory Issues: Tobacco smoke can lead to chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and other respiratory problems.Cardiovascular Disease: Smoking is a significant risk factor for heart disease and stroke.Oral Health Problems: Smokeless tobacco products can lead to oral cancer and dental issues.</string>


    <string name="p47">Ocimum basilicum</string>
    <string name="l47">Marvo</string>
    <string name="s47">Ocimum basilicum</string>
    <string name="f47">Lamiaceae (Mint family)</string>
    <string name="d47">Ocimum basilicum, commonly known as basil, is a fragrant herb known for its distinctive aroma and culinary uses.Basil plants can vary in size, but they typically grow as small to medium-sized annual herbs.The leaves are green, oval, and have a smooth texture. They are arranged oppositely on the stems.Basil plants produce small, white or purple flowers in clusters.</string>
    <string name="dt47">Basil is believed to have originated in India, but it is now grown and cultivated in various parts of the world.It thrives in warm, tropical climates and is commonly found in Mediterranean, Southeast Asian, and other regions with suitable growing conditions.Basil is also popular in home gardens and culinary herb gardens in temperate regions.</string>
    <string name="m47">Basil has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Chinese medicine.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Anti-Inflammatory: Basil is believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and may be used to alleviate inflammation and related conditions.Digestive Health: It is used to support digestion and relieve digestive discomfort.Respiratory Health: Basil may help with respiratory issues and coughs.Stress Reduction: In some traditional systems, basil is used to reduce stress and anxiety.Basil is also valued for its aromatic and soothing properties in herbal teas and aromatherapy.</string>
    <string name="b47">Basil is a versatile culinary herb used to flavor a wide range of dishes, including Italian pesto, Thai curries, and salads.It is rich in essential oils, including eugenol, which gives basil its distinctive aroma and potential health benefits.Basil is a source of vitamins (such as vitamin K) and minerals (including iron, calcium, and magnesium).It contains antioxidants, which can help protect cells from oxidative damage.</string>
    <string name="se47">Basil is generally considered safe when consumed in normal culinary amounts.Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to basil and may experience skin rashes or digestive discomfort after consumption.Excessive use of basil supplements or concentrated basil oil may lead to potential side effects.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should consume basil in moderation, and it\'s advisable to consult with a healthcare provider if there are specific concerns or medical conditions.</string>


    <string name="p48">Pennisetum americanum</string>
    <string name="l48">Bajro</string>
    <string name="s48">Pennisetum americanum</string>
    <string name="f48">Poaceae (Grass family)</string>
    <string name="d48">Pearl Millet is a hardy, annual cereal crop known for its tolerance to drought and hot temperatures.It is characterized by tall, slender stems that can reach heights of 2-4 meters.The leaves are long, linear, and gray-green in color.The seeds, which are the edible part of the plant, are small, round to oval, and typically cream-colored or pale yellow.</string>
    <string name="dt48">Pearl Millet is believed to have originated in Africa, particularly in the Sahel region.It is a staple food in many arid and semi-arid regions of Africa and the Indian subcontinent.It is also grown in parts of the Americas and other regions with similar climatic conditions</string>
    <string name="m48">Pearl Millet is primarily cultivated as a food crop, and its medicinal uses are limited compared to its use as a staple grain.Some traditional uses include:Digestive Health: Pearl Millet is considered easy to digest and is sometimes recommended for individuals with digestive sensitivities.Nutritional Support: It is a good source of dietary fiber and essential nutrients, such as iron and B vitamins.While it is valued for its nutritional content, it is not typically used for specific medicinal purposes.</string>
    <string name="b48">Pearl Millet offers several benefits as a dietary staple:Nutrient-Rich: It is rich in essential nutrients, including carbohydrates, dietary fiber, protein, iron, and B vitamins.Gluten-Free: Pearl Millet is naturally gluten-free, making it suitable for those with gluten sensitivities or celiac disease.Drought Tolerance: It is well-suited to regions with limited water resources due to its drought tolerance.Versatility: Pearl Millet can be used in various culinary preparations, including flatbreads, porridge, and as a grain for cooking.</string>
    <string name="se48">Pearl Millet is considered safe for consumption when prepared and cooked properly.Some individuals may have allergies or sensitivities to millet grains, although such cases are relatively rare.As with any dietary change, it\'s important to incorporate millet into the diet gradually to ensure it is well-tolerated.</string>


    <string name="p49">Pergularia daemia</string>
    <string name="l49">Nagladudheli</string>
    <string name="s49">Pergularia daemia</string>
    <string name="f49">Apocynaceae (Dogbane family)</string>
    <string name="d49">Pergularia daemia is a climbing or trailing perennial plant known for its vine-like growth.It typically has slender stems with twining characteristics that allow it to climb over other vegetation.The leaves are simple, opposite, and lance-shaped.The flowers of Pergularia daemia are small, pale greenish-yellow, and arranged in clusters.The plant produces slender, elongated fruits that contain seeds with a tuft of silky hairs, aiding in wind dispersal.</string>
    <string name="dt49">Pergularia daemia is native to various parts of Asia, including India, Sri Lanka, and some Southeast Asian countries.It can also be found in other tropical and subtropical regions around the world.</string>
    <string name="m49">Pergularia daemia has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and traditional Indian medicine.Some traditional medicinal uses include:Anti-Inflammatory: It is used for its potential anti-inflammatory properties.Digestive Health: In some cultures, it is used to address digestive issues and as a mild laxative.Respiratory Health: Pergularia daemia may be used for respiratory conditions and coughs.It is also believed to have potential benefits for skin ailments.</string>
    <string name="b49">Pergularia daemia is traditionally valued for its potential health benefits, but more scientific research is needed to confirm these effects.Some compounds found in the plant, such as alkaloids and flavonoids, may contribute to its medicinal properties.</string>
    <string name="se49">Specific side effects or safety concerns related to Pergularia daemia may not be well-documented in scientific literature.As with any herbal remedy, it\'s important to exercise caution and consult with a healthcare provider, especially if you have underlying health conditions, are pregnant or breastfeeding, or are considering the use of Pergularia daemia for medicinal purposes.The plant should be used under the guidance of a knowledgeable practitioner, as improper use or dosage may lead to adverse effects.</string>


    <string name="p50">Phoenix sylvestris</string>
    <string name="l50">Khajuri</string>
    <string name="s50">Phoenix sylvestris</string>
    <string name="f50">Arecaceae (Palm family)</string>
    <string name="d50">Phoenix sylvestris is a species of palm tree known for its tall, slender trunk and feathery, pinnate leaves.It can reach heights of up to 20-25 meters.The leaves are green and arching, with numerous linear leaflets that give them a feathery appearance.The trunk of Phoenix sylvestris is grayish and covered in persistent leaf bases.The fruit of this palm tree is known as "silver dates" and is small, oval, and yellowish or reddish when ripe</string>
    <string name="dt50">Phoenix sylvestris is native to the Indian subcontinent, including India, Pakistan, and Bangladesh.It is also cultivated in other parts of Asia and in some tropical and subtropical regions around the world.Date Palms are commonly found in arid and semi-arid regions.</string>
    <string name="m50">While the primary use of Phoenix sylvestris is for its edible fruits, it has some traditional medicinal uses in Ayurvedic and traditional medicine systems:Digestive Health: Date Palm fruits and sap are used to promote digestive health and relieve constipation.Cooling Effect: In Ayurveda, the pulp of the ripe fruit is considered cooling and is used to alleviate heat-related conditions.Laxative: Date Palm sap (toddy) is used as a mild laxative.Nutrient Source: The fruit is a source of vitamins, minerals, and natural sugars</string>
    <string name="b50">Phoenix sylvestris offers several benefits:Nutritional Value: Date Palm fruits are rich in essential nutrients, including dietary fiber, vitamins (such as vitamin A and vitamin C), and minerals (including potassium and magnesium).Energy Boost: The natural sugars in dates provide a quick source of energy.Hydration: Dates have a high water content, helping to keep the body hydrated.Iron Content: Dates are a good source of iron, making them beneficial for individuals with iron-deficiency anemia.Natural Sweetener: Date palms provide a natural sweetener that can be used in cooking and baking.</string>
    <string name="se50">Date Palm fruits are generally safe for consumption when eaten in moderation.Overconsumption of dates can lead to excess calorie intake, potentially contributing to weight gain.Some individuals may be sensitive to the natural sugars in dates and may need to monitor their intake, especially if they have diabetes or other blood sugar-related issues.It\'s essential to ensure that date palms are grown and harvested under hygienic conditions to prevent contamination.</string>

    <string name="p51">Piper betle</string>
    <string name="l51">Nagarval</string>
    <string name="s51">Piper betle</string>
    <string name="f51">Piperaceae</string>
    <string name="d51">Betel Leaf is a perennial, evergreen vine-like plant known for its heart-shaped, glossy leaves.The leaves are typically bright to dark green and are often used for wrapping various ingredients to create a popular chewing mixture called "paan."Betel Leaf plants can grow up to 1-1.5 meters in height.The plant produces small, inconspicuous flowers in spikes.</string>
    <string name="dt51">Betel Leaf is native to South and Southeast Asia, including countries like India, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, Indonesia, and Thailand.It is widely cultivated and used in various cultural practices, especially in South Asia and parts of Southeast Asia.</string>
    <string name="m51">Betel Leaf has a long history of traditional medicinal and cultural use:Digestive Aid: It is commonly used as a digestive aid, as chewing betel leaves with various ingredients is believed to help with digestion and relieve stomach discomfort.Mouth Freshener: Betel Leaf is known for its mouth-freshening properties and is often chewed for this purpose.Antiseptic: Betel Leaf is used topically for its antiseptic properties and may be applied to minor cuts and wounds.Respiratory Health: In some traditional systems, it is used to alleviate symptoms of respiratory conditions.Aphrodisiac: In some cultures, betel leaves are believed to have aphrodisiac effects.Traditional Rituals: Betel Leaf has significant cultural and ritualistic importance in various regions and is offered during ceremonies and social gatherings.</string>
    <string name="se51">While betel leaves are generally safe when used in moderation, there are some potential side effects to be aware of:Staining: Chewing betel leaves can lead to teeth and mouth staining, which can be difficult to remove.Oral Health: Excessive use of betel leaves with additives like areca nut and tobacco can contribute to oral health problems, including gum disease and oral cancer.Addiction: Some preparations of betel leaf may contain addictive substances, such as tobacco or areca nut, which can lead to addiction.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use betel leaves with caution, as some additives may be harmful to the fetus or newborn.</string>
    <string name="b51">Betel Leaf is valued for its potential health benefits:Antioxidants: It contains antioxidants, such as hydroxychavicol, which can help combat oxidative stress.Anti-Inflammatory: Some compounds in betel leaves may have anti-inflammatory properties.Oral Health: Chewing betel leaves is believed to promote oral health and freshen the breath.Digestive Health: Betel leaves may aid in digestion and provide relief from indigestion.Cultural Significance: It plays a crucial role in cultural and social traditions.</string>

    <string name="p52">Piper longum</string>
    <string name="l52">Lindipipar</string>
    <string name="s52">Piper longum</string>
    <string name="f52">Piperaceae</string>
    <string name="d52">Piper longum is a perennial climbing vine with slender, elongated spikes of tiny flowers.It produces elongated, cylindrical, and slender spikes of fruits that resemble catkins.The fruits are harvested for their peppery flavor and are dried to create long pepper spice.The leaves of the plant are heart-shaped, and it has a woody stem.</string>
    <string name="dt52">Piper longum is native to South Asia, particularly India, and it is also found in Southeast Asian countries.It is widely cultivated in tropical regions around the world, including parts of Africa and the Americas.</string>
    <string name="m52">Piper longum has a rich history of use in traditional medicine systems, especially in Ayurveda, where it is highly valued:Digestive Health: It is commonly used to improve digestion, alleviate indigestion, and promote appetite.Respiratory Health: Piper longum is used to address respiratory issues, such as coughs and colds.Anti-Inflammatory: It is believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and is used for joint health.Enhancement of Bioavailability: Piper longum is known for its bioavailability-enhancing effects when combined with other herbs and substances, allowing the body to better absorb nutrients and medicinal compounds.In Ayurveda, it is considered one of the best herbs for stimulating the digestive fire (agni) and improving overall digestive function.</string>
    <string name="se52">Piper longum is generally considered safe when consumed in culinary amounts and for short-term medicinal use.However, excessive or prolonged use may lead to potential side effects:Gastrointestinal Distress: High doses may cause digestive discomfort, such as gastric irritation or diarrhea.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive to long pepper and may experience allergic reactions.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use long pepper with caution and consult a healthcare provider.Interactions: Long pepper may interact with certain medications, so it\'s important to consult a healthcare professional if you are taking any prescription drugs.</string>
    <string name="b52">Piper longum offers several potential health benefits:Digestive Support: It is used to improve digestion, relieve flatulence, and stimulate appetite.Respiratory Health: It may help with coughs, asthma, and other respiratory conditions.Anti-Inflammatory: Piper longum is believed to have anti-inflammatory effects, which can be beneficial for joint health.Bioavailability Enhancement: It enhances the absorption of nutrients and bioactive compounds from other foods and herbs.Antioxidant Properties: Some studies suggest that it may have antioxidant properties, helping to combat oxidative stress.Long pepper is used as a spice and flavoring agent in various cuisines, adding a pungent and aromatic quality to dishes.</string>

    <string name="p53">Piper nigrum</string>
    <string name="l53">Mare</string>
    <string name="s53">Piper nigrum</string>
    <string name="f53">Piperaceae</string>
    <string name="d53">Black Pepper is a perennial climbing vine characterized by heart-shaped leaves and small flowers.The fruits of Piper nigrum are what we commonly know as peppercorns.These peppercorns are green when harvested but turn black when dried, giving the spice its name.Black Pepper is known for its pungent and spicy flavor and is a widely used spice in culinary applications.</string>
    <string name="dt53">Piper nigrum is native to South Asia, specifically the Western Ghats region of India.It is now cultivated in tropical regions around the world, including Southeast Asia, South America, and Africa.Black Pepper is one of the most traded spices globally.</string>
    <string name="m53">Black Pepper has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, where it is valued for its potential health benefits:Digestive Aid: It is commonly used to improve digestion, alleviate indigestion, and promote appetite.Antioxidant Properties: Black Pepper contains antioxidants, such as piperine, which can help combat oxidative stress.Anti-Inflammatory: Piperine in Black Pepper is believed to have anti-inflammatory effects.Enhancement of Nutrient Absorption: Piperine can enhance the absorption of nutrients from the digestive tract, making it beneficial when combined with certain supplements and foods</string>
    <string name="se53">Black Pepper is generally considered safe when used as a spice in cooking.However, excessive consumption or high doses of concentrated Black Pepper supplements may lead to potential side effects:Gastrointestinal Distress: Consuming too much Black Pepper can cause gastric irritation or digestive discomfort.Interactions: Piperine in Black Pepper may interact with certain medications, affecting their absorption and effectiveness.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to Black Pepper and may experience allergic reactions.Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use Black Pepper in moderation, and it\'s advisable to consult a healthcare provider if there are specific concerns or medical conditions.</string>
    <string name="b53">Black Pepper offers several potential health benefits:Digestive Health: It is used to improve digestion, relieve flatulence, and stimulate appetite.Antioxidant Effects: The antioxidants in Black Pepper can help protect cells from damage caused by free radicals.Enhanced Nutrient Absorption: Piperine, a compound in Black Pepper, enhances the bioavailability of other nutrients, such as curcumin from turmeric.Respiratory Health: Some traditional uses include using Black Pepper to alleviate respiratory conditions and coughs.Culinary Use: Black Pepper is a staple spice in many cuisines, adding flavor and depth to dishes.</string>

    <string name="p54">Plantago ovata Forsk</string>
    <string name="l54">Isabgol</string>
    <string name="s54">Plantago ovata Forsk</string>
    <string name="f54">Plantaginaceae</string>
    <string name="d54">Psyllium is an annual herbaceous plant known for its tiny, gel-coated seeds, which are the primary source of psyllium husk, a soluble fiber.The plant itself is small and produces narrow, lance-shaped leaves with parallel veins.Psyllium flowers are small and inconspicuous, typically appearing as dense, cylindrical spikes.</string>
    <string name="dt54">Plantago ovata Forsk is native to the Mediterranean region, but it is also cultivated in various countries, including India, Pakistan, and some parts of the United States.India is one of the leading producers of psyllium in the world.</string>
    <string name="m54">Psyllium is widely recognized for its medicinal uses, particularly as a source of dietary fiber:Digestive Health: It is commonly used to relieve constipation and promote regular bowel movements. Psyllium husk absorbs water in the intestines, forming a gel-like substance that softens stool and aids in its passage.Diarrhea Management: Contrary to its use for constipation, psyllium can also be used to manage diarrhea. It helps absorb excess water in the intestines and solidify loose stools.Lowering Cholesterol: Some studies suggest that psyllium may help reduce LDL cholesterol levels, which can benefit heart health.Blood Sugar Management: Psyllium may help stabilize blood sugar levels in individuals with diabetes by slowing the absorption of sugar from the digestive tract.Weight Management: The fiber in psyllium can help promote a feeling of fullness, potentially aiding in weight management.Psyllium is also used in some herbal and traditional medicine systems for its potential health benefits.</string>
    <string name="se54">When used as directed, psyllium is generally considered safe for most individuals.However, there are some potential side effects and considerations to be aware of:Gastrointestinal Effects: Psyllium can cause gas, bloating, and abdominal discomfort in some individuals, especially if taken in excessive amounts.Allergic Reactions: Rarely, individuals may be allergic to psyllium and experience symptoms like itching, swelling, or difficulty breathing.Fluid Intake: It\'s important to drink plenty of water when taking psyllium supplements to prevent choking or intestinal blockages.Medication Interactions: Psyllium can interfere with the absorption of certain medications, so it's important to take medications separately, as directed by a healthcare provider.</string>
    <string name="b54">Psyllium offers several potential health benefits:Relief from Constipation: Psyllium husk is highly effective in relieving constipation by adding bulk and softness to stool.Lowering Cholesterol: It may help reduce LDL cholesterol levels when used as part of a heart-healthy diet.Blood Sugar Control: Psyllium can contribute to better blood sugar control in individuals with diabetes.Weight Management: The feeling of fullness it provides can aid in weight management and portion control.Digestive Health: It promotes overall digestive health by regulating bowel movements.</string>

    <string name="p55">Plumbago zeylanica</string>
    <string name="l55">Chitrak</string>
    <string name="s55">Plumbago zeylanica</string>
    <string name="f55">Plumbaginaceae</string>
    <string name="d55">Plumbago zeylanica is a perennial shrub known for its slender, trailing, or climbing stems.The leaves are simple, lance-shaped, and arranged alternately along the stems.The flowers of this plant are tubular and typically blue to violet in color, although white and pink varieties are also found.The fruit is a capsule containing small, winged seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt55">Plumbago zeylanica is native to tropical and subtropical regions and is found in various parts of Asia, Africa, and the Americas.It is commonly found in India, Sri Lanka, Southeast Asia, and parts of Africa.The plant is often cultivated as an ornamental due to its attractive flowers.</string>
    <string name="m55">Plumbago zeylanica has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, where it is valued for its potential medicinal properties:Digestive Health: It is used to stimulate digestion and alleviate digestive discomfort, such as indigestion and flatulence.Respiratory Health: Plumbago zeylanica is used in some traditional remedies to address respiratory conditions like coughs and asthma.Antimicrobial: It is believed to have antimicrobial properties and has been used for various infections.Anti-Inflammatory: The plant is used topically for its potential anti-inflammatory effects.Skin Conditions: In some cultures, it is applied externally to address skin ailments.Aphrodisiac: Plumbago zeylanica is also believed to have aphrodisiac properties in certain traditional systems.</string>
    <string name="se55">Plumbago zeylanica should be used with caution, and its use should be supervised by a knowledgeable practitioner:Toxicity: The plant contains toxic compounds, including plumbagin, which can be harmful if ingested in large amounts.Skin Irritation: The sap of the plant can cause skin irritation and should be handled with care.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should avoid or use this plant with extreme caution due to its potential toxicity.</string>
    <string name="b55">Plumbago zeylanica offers several potential health benefits:Digestive Support: It is used to promote digestion and relieve digestive discomfort.Respiratory Relief: Some traditional uses include addressing respiratory conditions.Antimicrobial: The plant is believed to have antimicrobial properties that may help combat infections.Anti-Inflammatory: It may have topical anti-inflammatory effects.Skin Health: Plumbago zeylanica is used for various skin conditions, although scientific evidence is limited.While it has traditional uses, scientific research on its efficacy and safety is limited, and more studies are needed to confirm its potential health benefits.</string>

    <string name="p56">Pongamia pinnata Pierre</string>
    <string name="l56">Karanj</string>
    <string name="s56">Pongamia pinnata Pierre</string>
    <string name="f56">Fabaceae </string>
    <string name="d56">Pongamia pinnata is a medium-sized to large, evergreen tree with a straight trunk and a rounded crown.The leaves are compound, with multiple leaflets arranged opposite each other on the leaf stalk.The flowers are white to pale purple and are typically borne in racemes.The fruit of Pongamia is a pod that contains seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt56">Pongamia pinnata is native to various parts of Asia, including India, Sri Lanka, Myanmar, and Indonesia.It is also found in some parts of Australia and has been introduced to several other tropical and subtropical regions around the world.</string>
    <string name="m56">Pongamia pinnata has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, where various parts of the tree are utilized for their potential medicinal properties:Skin Conditions: The oil extracted from Pongamia seeds, known as "Karanja oil," is used topically for its potential benefits in treating skin conditions, such as eczema, psoriasis, and fungal infections.Wound Healing: Karanja oil may promote wound healing and reduce inflammation when applied to minor cuts and wounds.Insect Repellent: The oil is also used as a natural insect repellent.Antiseptic: Pongamia extracts are sometimes used for their antiseptic properties.In Ayurvedic medicine, various parts of the tree, including the seeds and bark, are used in different formulations for their potential therapeutic effects</string>
    <string name="se56">When used topically, Karanja oil is generally considered safe for most individuals.However, there are a few considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to Karanja oil, so it\'s advisable to perform a patch test before widespread use.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use Karanja oil with caution and consult with a healthcare provider.Oral Consumption: Consuming the oil internally is not recommended, as it may have toxic effects in large amounts.Interactions: Karanja oil may interact with certain medications, so consult with a healthcare provider if you are taking medications.</string>
    <string name="b56">Pongamia pinnata offers several potential health and practical benefits:Skin Health: Karanja oil, derived from the seeds, is known for its potential benefits in promoting healthy skin and addressing various skin conditions.Wound Care: It may help with wound healing and reduce the risk of infection.Natural Insect Repellent: Pongamia oil is used as a natural alternative to chemical insect repellents.Biodiesel: The seeds of Pongamia contain oil that can be processed into biodiesel, making it a valuable resource for sustainable energy production.</string>

    <string name="p57">Ricinus communis</string>
    <string name="l57">Arandi</string>
    <string name="s57">Ricinus communis</string>
    <string name="f57">Euphorbiaceae</string>
    <string name="d57">Ricinus communis is a large, fast-growing, and perennial woody shrub or small tree.It is known for its palmately lobed leaves, often with a reddish stem, and a central stalk.The plant produces clusters of small, inconspicuous green or red flowers.The most distinctive feature is its spiky fruit capsules, which contain seeds known as castor beans.</string>
    <string name="dt57">Ricinus communis is native to tropical and subtropical regions of Africa and Asia.It has become naturalized in many parts of the world and can be found in various temperate and tropical regions.In some areas, it is cultivated as an ornamental plant, while in others, it is considered an invasive species.</string>
    <string name="m57">Ricinus communis has a history of medicinal use, primarily for its seeds and oil:Laxative: Castor oil, derived from the seeds, has been used as a powerful laxative for relieving constipation.Induction of Labor: Castor oil has also been used to induce labor in pregnant women, although its use for this purpose is now discouraged due to potential risks.Anti-Inflammatory: The oil has been applied topically for its anti-inflammatory properties.Pain Relief: Castor oil packs are sometimes used for pain relief and to reduce inflammation.It\'s important to note that while castor oil has medicinal uses, it should be used with caution, and medical guidance is advised, especially for internal use.</string>
    <string name="se57">Castor oil should be used with caution, and internal use should be supervised by a healthcare provider:Laxative Effect: Consuming castor oil can lead to strong and sometimes uncomfortable bowel movements. It may cause cramps and diarrhea.Dehydration: Excessive use of castor oil can lead to dehydration due to fluid loss through diarrhea.Pregnancy: Internal use of castor oil is discouraged during pregnancy due to its potential to induce labor and associated risks.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be allergic to castor oil, leading to skin rashes or other allergic symptoms.Topical Irritation: When applied topically, castor oil may cause skin irritation in some people.</string>
    <string name="b57">Ricinus communis offers several potential benefits:Laxative: Castor oil is a potent laxative and can be used to relieve occasional constipation.Moisturizer: Castor oil is used as a moisturizer for the skin and hair due to its emollient properties.Anti-Inflammatory: When applied topically, it may help reduce inflammation and soothe skin conditions.Pain Relief: Castor oil packs are sometimes used for pain management, such as for muscle aches and joint discomfort.</string>

    <string name="p58">Santalum album</string>
    <string name="l58">Chandan</string>
    <string name="s58">Santalum album</string>
    <string name="f58">Santalaceae</string>
    <string name="d58">Santalum album is a small to medium-sized evergreen tree known for its aromatic heartwood, which is highly prized for its fragrance.The leaves are simple, opposite, and elliptical in shape.The tree produces small, inconspicuous flowers that are often pale yellow to purple.The heartwood of the tree, which is rich in essential oils, is the most valuable part of the plant.</string>
    <string name="dt58">Santalum album is native to the Indian subcontinent, particularly India, Sri Lanka, and certain parts of Indonesia.It is also cultivated in other tropical regions with suitable climates, such as Australia and some Pacific islands.</string>
    <string name="m58">Santalum album has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, primarily for its aromatic heartwood:Aromatherapy: The essential oil extracted from sandalwood is used in aromatherapy for its calming and soothing properties. It is believed to reduce stress and anxiety.Skin Care: Sandalwood oil is used in skincare products and traditional remedies for its potential benefits for the skin, such as reducing acne and inflammation.Antiseptic: It is used as an antiseptic for minor wounds and skin infections.Anti-Inflammatory: Sandalwood oil is believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and is used topically for conditions like eczema and psoriasis.Sandalwood paste, made from the heartwood, is also applied topically for various skin-related issues.</string>
    <string name="se58">Sandalwood is generally considered safe for external use when used in moderate amounts.However, there are some considerations:Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to sandalwood oil, leading to skin irritation or allergic symptoms.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use sandalwood oil with caution, and it\'s advisable to consult a healthcare provider.Essential Oil Purity: Ensure that you are using pure, high-quality sandalwood essential oil, as adulterated or synthetic oils may cause adverse reactions.</string>
    <string name="b58">Santalum album offers several potential benefits:Aromatherapy: Sandalwood essential oil is used in aromatherapy for its calming and stress-reducing effects.Skin Health: It is valued for its potential benefits in skincare, such as reducing acne, soothing irritation, and improving skin tone.Fragrance: Sandalwood\'s sweet and woody aroma is used in perfumes, incense, and cosmetic products.Traditional and Cultural Uses: Sandalwood has cultural and religious significance in various traditions and is used in rituals and ceremonies.</string>

    <string name="p59">Secunnega leucopyrus</string>
    <string name="l59">Shirni</string>
    <string name="s59">Secunnega leucopyrus</string>
    <string name="f59">Apocynaceae</string>
    <string name="d59">Secunnega leucopyrus is a small to medium-sized evergreen tree or shrub that typically reaches a height of 3 to 12 meters. The plant has simple, opposite leaves that are glossy and elliptical. Its bark is pale gray to brown, and it exudes a milky latex when cut. The plant produces small, fragrant, tubular, white or pale yellow flowers. The fruit is a pair of follicles, each containing numerous seeds with a tuft of silky hairs to aid in wind dispersal.</string>
    <string name="dt59">Secunnega leucopyrus is native to the Indian subcontinent and is commonly found in India, Sri Lanka, and other nearby regions. It prefers tropical and subtropical climates and can be found in both dry and moist deciduous forests.</string>
    <string name="m59">Various parts of Secunnega leucopyrus have been traditionally used in Ayurvedic and folk medicine for their medicinal properties. Some of the common medicinal uses include:Asthma and Respiratory Issues: The latex of the plant is used to relieve symptoms of asthma and other respiratory ailments. It is often applied topically on the chest.Anti-inflammatory Properties: The leaves and latex of the plant are known for their anti-inflammatory properties and are used to treat various inflammatory conditions.Wound Healing: The latex is also applied to wounds to promote healing and prevent infection.Laxative: The plant\'s bark and latex are sometimes used as a mild laxative.Diuretic: In some traditional practices, it is used as a diuretic to increase urine production.Fever and Malaria: The plant has been used in the treatment of fevers, including those associated with malaria.</string>
    <string name="se59">While Secunnega leucopyrus has been used in traditional medicine, it is essential to note that the plant\'s use and potential side effects may vary from person to person. The latex of the plant can cause skin irritation in some individuals. Ingesting excessive amounts of the plant or its latex may lead to digestive discomfort or diarrhea. Like any herbal remedy, it is important to consult with a healthcare professional before using it, especially if you have underlying health conditions or are taking other medications.</string>
    <string name="b59">The medicinal uses of Secunnega leucopyrus offer various potential benefits, especially in traditional and alternative medicine systems. Some of the benefits include relief from respiratory ailments, inflammation, and wounds, as well as potential use as a laxative and diuretic.</string>

    <string name="p60">Senna alexandrina </string>
    <string name="l60">Sonamukhi</string>
    <string name="s60">Senna alexandrina </string>
    <string name="f60">Fabaceae </string>
    <string name="d60">Senna alexandrina is a small shrub known for its distinctive pinnate leaves and bright yellow flowers.The leaves are characterized by multiple leaflets arranged opposite each other on the leaf stalk.The plant produces elongated, cylindrical pods that contain the seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt60">Senna alexandrina is native to North Africa, particularly the Nile Delta region in Egypt.It is also cultivated in various parts of the world, including India and some parts of the Americas, for its medicinal properties.</string>
    <string name="m60">Senna alexandrina has a long history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly as a natural laxative:Laxative: It is widely used as a natural and effective laxative to relieve constipation. The compounds in Senna, called anthraquinones, stimulate bowel movements.Colon Cleansing: Some use it for colon cleansing and before certain medical procedures, such as colonoscopies.It is important to note that Senna should only be used for short-term relief of constipation and under the guidance of a healthcare provider.</string>
    <string name="se60">While Senna can be effective for constipation relief, it is not without potential side effects and should be used with caution:Gastrointestinal Discomfort: Some individuals may experience abdominal cramps, discomfort, or diarrhea when using Senna.Dependency: Prolonged or frequent use of Senna may lead to laxative dependency, where the body becomes reliant on it for regular bowel movements.Electrolyte Imbalance: Excessive use of Senna can lead to electrolyte imbalances, such as low potassium levels.Dehydration: Diarrhea caused by Senna can lead to dehydration, especially in vulnerable populations like the elderly.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should avoid Senna or use it only under the guidance of a healthcare provider.</string>
    <string name="b60">Senna alexandrina offers the primary benefit of effective and prompt relief from constipation when used as directed.It is generally considered safe when used in the short term for occasional constipation.</string>

    <string name="p61">Senna auriculata</string>
    <string name="l61">Aval</string>
    <string name="s61">Senna auriculata</string>
    <string name="f61">Fabaceae </string>
    <string name="d61">Senna auriculata is a small, woody shrub known for its pinnate leaves and bright yellow flowers.The leaves are characterized by multiple pairs of leaflets arranged opposite each other on the leaf stalk.The plant produces slender, cylindrical pods that contain the seeds.</string>
    <string name="dt61">Senna auriculata is native to the Indian subcontinent and is commonly found in India and Sri Lanka.It is also cultivated in other parts of Asia, such as Thailand and Malaysia, for its medicinal properties.The plant is often grown as a garden ornamental due to its attractive flowers.</string>
    <string name="m61">Senna auriculata has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and Siddha medicine:Diabetes Management: It is used to help manage diabetes by potentially lowering blood sugar levels.Digestive Health: Senna auriculata is used as a mild laxative and is believed to promote healthy digestion and relieve constipation.Skin Health: In some traditional remedies, the plant is used for its potential benefits for skin conditions like acne and eczema.Antioxidant Properties: The plant is also believed to possess antioxidant properties.It\'s important to note that while Senna auriculata has traditional uses, scientific research on its efficacy and safety is limited, and more studies are needed to confirm its potential health benefits.</string>
    <string name="b61">Senna auriculata offers several potential health benefits:Diabetes Management: It may help regulate blood sugar levels and improve insulin sensitivity.Digestive Support: Senna auriculata is used for its mild laxative effects and may help with occasional constipation.Skin Health: It is valued in some traditional remedies for promoting healthy skin.Antioxidant Effects: The plant may offer antioxidant protection against oxidative stress.</string>
    <string name="se61">While Senna auriculata is generally considered safe when used in moderation, there are some considerations and potential side effects:Gastrointestinal Effects: Excessive use may lead to abdominal cramps, diarrhea, or gastrointestinal discomfort.Dehydration: Diarrhea caused by Senna auriculata can lead to dehydration, so it\'s important to stay well-hydrated.Electrolyte Imbalance: Prolonged or frequent use may result in electrolyte imbalances, such as low potassium levels.Pregnancy and Nursing: Pregnant and breastfeeding women should use Senna auriculata with caution and preferably under the guidance of a healthcare provider.Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may be sensitive or allergic to the plant and may experience skin rashes or other allergic symptoms.</string>

    <string name="p62">Senna tora</string>
    <string name="l62">Kunwadiyo</string>
    <string name="s62">Senna tora</string>
    <string name="f62">Fabaceae </string>
    <string name="d62">Senna tora is an annual herbaceous plant known for its pinnate leaves and distinctive sickle-shaped pods.The leaves consist of multiple pairs of leaflets arranged opposite each other along the leaf stalk.The plant produces bright yellow flowers with five petals.The pods are slender, curved, and brown when mature, resembling a sickle, which gives the plant its common name.</string>
    <string name="dt62">Senna tora is native to various parts of Asia and is found in countries such as India, China, and the Philippines.It is also considered an invasive weed in some regions.</string>
    <string name="m62">Senna tora has a history of use in traditional medicine systems, particularly in Ayurveda and Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM):Laxative: The plant is used as a natural laxative, primarily due to the presence of compounds called anthraquinones, which stimulate bowel movements.Eye Health: In TCM, Senna tora is used for its potential benefits to eye health and to address conditions like conjunctivitis.Anti-Inflammatory: It is believed to have anti-inflammatory properties and is used topically for skin ailments.The plant is valued for its mild laxative effects and is often used to relieve constipation.</string>
    <string name="b62">Senna tora offers several potential benefits:Laxative Effect: It is an effective natural laxative for relieving occasional constipation.Eye Health: In TCM, it is used for maintaining eye health and addressing certain eye conditions.Skin Health: The plant may have topical anti-inflammatory effects and is used for various skin conditions.</string>
    <string name="se62">Senna tora should be used with caution, and its use should be supervised:Gastrointestinal Discomfort: Excessive use may lead to abdominal cramps, discomfort, or diarrhea.Dehydration: Diarrhea caused by Senna tora can lead to dehydration, so it\'s important to stay well-hydrated.Electrolyte Imbalance: Prolonged or frequent use may result in electrolyte imbalances, such as low potassium levels.Dependency: Frequent use of laxatives, including Senna tora, can lead to laxative dependency, where the body relies on them for regular bowel movements.</string>

</resources>